<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Juan's Dev Journal</title>
    <atom:link href="http://dev.endgamestudio.com//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
    <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com/</link>
    <description>Dev journal, snippets, and rants.</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 19:27:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <generator>Wintersmith - https://github.com/jnordberg/wintersmith</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 36</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2015-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 19:27:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2015-16/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 36&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;weeknotes&quot;&gt;Weeknotes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managing Distractions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;managing-distractions&quot;&gt;Managing Distractions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I fail at managing distractions A LOT. When a fellow developer needs my help, I’ll help. Even though I probably should finish my current train of thought before I switch contexts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like that’s the trick though; switching contexts successfully. If you can switch context, finish the new task, than switch back seamlessly… you’re amazing.  Most of us, I imagine, can’t do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of my problem is how I use my To Do list, Things.  I kind of wished there was a way to mark something as “current” or “in progress”, and only have the ability to mark one todo as such. It would also keep a memory of the order you worked on tasks. So, switching from task A to task B would be visible to you when you finished Task B and needed to return to task A.  It’s also not very easy to enter notes in Things. I love things and this is probably an edge case for many todo apps. This just means I need to have some sort of “context journal”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started that this week. I’ll report back on how it’s helping.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 35</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2015-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 19:27:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2015-15/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 35&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;weeknotes&quot;&gt;Weeknotes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;App Builds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CommonJS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;app-builds&quot;&gt;App builds&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an application grows, especially in its infancy, there needs to be some processes in place to help achieve and maintain goals for the build process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We recently split off all our web components into their own repo and this caused all kinds of madness. It was something we couldn’t foresee and, therefore, it wasn’t something we could have done better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, when something we built ends up being a blocker for current work, there needs to be some sort of &lt;a href=&quot;http://dev.endgamestudio.com/articles/Meetup-talk-aar/&quot;&gt;AAR&lt;/a&gt; where we figure out what went wrong and how to avoid it in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don’t have a dev ops person… well, not explicitly anyway. I wouldn’t say we &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; have one, but we should remove someone from a sprint when something huge happens, something like changing our repos this extensively. This person’s sole responsibility is to monitor and maintain the build. They should document and test the build until it satisfactory. A lot of people will have a problem with this because the velocity of the next sprint will be negatively affected. It’s a tough situation. I’m curious how similar size teams handle this situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;commonjs&quot;&gt;CommonJS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had to familiarize myself with how CommonJS works a bit this week. I don’t mean the &lt;code&gt;require&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;exports&lt;/code&gt; keywords but more how it looks for files and which &lt;em&gt;thing&lt;/em&gt; to use when there could be multiples. Maybe I’m not looking right but I couldn’t seem to find much on this type of information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 34</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2015-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2015 19:27:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2015-14/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 34&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;weeknotes&quot;&gt;Weeknotes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;StealJS yet again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Promises/Deferreds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning about WebWorkers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;stealjs-yet-again&quot;&gt;StealJS yet again&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent some time working on the build process for The Art Project. It seems like i was using the incorrect distribution of CanJS. Once i switched to AMD, things started working. Im still having problems though. Now the stache plugin is returning some funky errors. Still debugging what the errors actually mean. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A question i have to bring up is why Steal doesn’t report better errors. Ill explain later as I’m still trying to make sure I
m on the right track. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;promises-and-deferreds&quot;&gt;Promises and deferreds&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was working on a dialog implementation using can.component. Example usage of the component’s api was given to me and I just had to build it. Im glad i was given these examples as it seriously open my mind to the real possibilities of deferreds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being able to use reject and resolve to trigger different callback without having to pass the callbacks to the dialog itself is genius. Ill be adding this to our component library asap. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;web-workers&quot;&gt;Web Workers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read a primer on web workers this week and I’m curious if they can be used to compile templates. I am using a pseudo model to manage a calendar widget, I bet this can be refactored to be a web worker as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s crazy how much the browser api and ECMA script combined have essentially become a programming environment like native mobile apps. Its cool and exciting, but also a little crazy. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 33</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2015-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 19:27:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2015-13/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 33&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bitovi Retreat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;bitovi-retreat&quot;&gt;Bitovi Retreat&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was my first retreat with the team and it was AMAZING. The first part of the week was basically a hackathon where we tried to work on stuff that we had proposed back in December. Most being tools to improve our Open Source products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project I worked on was building a component library for CanJS.  Other teams worked on improving DocumentJS, CanJS, and more.  The component library ended up using many of the improvements to help present the work in a useful way. DocumentJS, for example, was great for creating the API docs that included demos of each component.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the work week, significant others were flown out for the weekend where we explored and enjoyed Austin Texas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was an amazing experience. There were long days but I can’t imagine a better group of people to spend loooong days with while getting some very cool stuff built.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 32</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2015-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2015 19:27:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2015-12/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 32&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scope creep&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;scope-creep&quot;&gt;Scope Creep&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I export my tasks from Jira and other work task management tools into Things. It’s easier because I can break up tasks into sizes that work better for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I noticed this past sprint that I added a single task to my workload. When I broke it out into individual tasks, it turned into three tasks. I then added documentation and test updates, which made it five tasks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After working on the first task, I had questions on changes which resulted in two more tasks.  These new tasks, after the final product was reviewed, resulted in a five more tasks. Keep in mind these are all minimal tasks. One could be something like “change color for text” while another could be something more involved but still as small as it could be. Something like “resolve merge conflicts”. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is really normal and I’m glad I aggregate my lists this way, specifically because it helps me respond to scope changes like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also interesting to see a task list turn into a hydra monster. One task turned into three which turned into five, which turned into seven, which is still not done and could continue growing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping track of these monsters is important, at some point (if it continues to grow), the wheel needs to get squeaky.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 31</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2015-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 10:52:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2015-11/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 31&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Six Months at Bitovi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CanJS Control&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CanJS and Steal Part 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;six-months-at-bitovi&quot;&gt;Six Months at Bitovi&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had my six month checkin this week. The realization that it’s been six months was weird. Time flies, man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The past six months have been amazing. My desire to learn more and improve is constantly satisfied and challenged. I get to work with some bad ass people working on some bad ass projects. I’m pretty excited that it’s only been six months, that means I’m having fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;canjs-control&quot;&gt;CanJS Control&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m trying out this pattern where, instead of adding more features to a component, I add the new feature as a &lt;a href=&quot;http://canjs.com/docs/can.Control.html&quot;&gt;can.Control&lt;/a&gt; that is designed to work specifically with the component.  Lately, we’ve been adding feature after feature to some components and they’re getting harder and harder to maintain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even after six months, I’m still learning new things about our open source tools like &lt;a href=&quot;http://canjs.com/&quot;&gt;CanJS&lt;/a&gt;. It &lt;em&gt;feels&lt;/em&gt; like this is a good solution but I can’t be certain until after it gets used for a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My other thought was to build additional functionality for a component &lt;em&gt;within&lt;/em&gt; another discrete component. Then, if this functionality is needed, all one has to do is add the other component and target the original component. I’m not sure how the linking part would work so I decided to stick with the can.Control for now. We’ll see how it works out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;canjs-and-steal-part-2&quot;&gt;CanJS and Steal Part 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After researching other CanJS projects, I figured out my problem with getting fixtures to work in my art project. Using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bitovi/canjs/releases/tag/v2.2.0&quot;&gt;new release of CanJS&lt;/a&gt;, I also had to update the paths in the Steal config file. Changing the paths meant updating every file I had old paths in. Once this was done, everything worked GREAT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I’m having problems with my routes, unrelated to the above though. I’m still getting familiar with how to write solid routes so it’s a little hard to debug. Also, the build isn’t actually building (I’m using Steal to load dependancies in the browser), and I need to verify my routes are good. So the first step is to make sure everything builds nicely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re heading to Austin this week for a Bitovi retreat (super excited!) so I’m going miss this weeks &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codeforcary.org/&quot;&gt;Code for Cary&lt;/a&gt; Meetup. I’m going to try and get a build working so we can have a prototype site running by the end of the week.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 30</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2015-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2015 19:27:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2015-10/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working outside&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;working-outside&quot;&gt;Working outside&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had our first nice-ish day this year. It was nice enough to leave the windows open all day and even sit on the porch and do some work. There are days where I miss the immediate interaction one can get when working at an office. Collaboration works so much cleaner, I think, in this environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remote work isn’t worse, it’s just different. This collaboration still exists, just over a wire. I don’t think it takes a “specific type of person” to be a remote worker, but it definitely requires a certain mindset. The rewards for being able to work this way are bountiful. One such benefit is working on your porch. ;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 29</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2015-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2015 19:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2015-09/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 29&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CanJS and StealJS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;canjs-and-stealjs&quot;&gt;CanJS and StealJS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got a chance to work on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/CodeForCary/minervas-box&quot;&gt;Art Finder project&lt;/a&gt; for Code for Cary and I thought I would continue getting prototypes working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For module loading, I am using StealJS. It’s the second time I’ve used it in a project with CanJS where I am using fixtures.  I’m a little behind on the two tools as far as how they work with each other. The biggest problem is StealJS chokes on &lt;code&gt;can.fixture.js&lt;/code&gt; because  CanJS 2.1.4 &lt;a href=&quot;https://forum.javascriptmvc.com/topic/can-fixture-stealjs&quot;&gt;doesn’t work with newest StealJS versions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m really bummed out by this and surprised. The solution is to use the CanJS minor branch but that causes other errors in my code and fixtures &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; won’t load.  This app won’t be live any time soon so there’s no real rush but it’s a little frustrating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll see how that goes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 28</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2015-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2015 19:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2015-08/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 28&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logging time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;StealJS with CanJS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;logging-time&quot;&gt;Logging time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder who really benefits from logging time. There are rarely tools that make it easy to capture time spent on projects, render time reports, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; add on other business specific options.  Never mind being cost effective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent a lot of time logging time and I was wondering how often time tracking is actually useful beyond the time spent tracking the actual time spent. More often I hear legal reasons than billing reasons and almost rarely hear productivity reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just sayin’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;firebase-s-firepad&quot;&gt;Firebase’s Firepad&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I built a quick app using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.firebase.com/&quot;&gt;Firebase’s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.firepad.io/&quot;&gt;Firepad tool&lt;/a&gt;. Firepad is a notepad with versioning (ish) and collaboration while using Firebase as the backend.  It’s pretty neat to have all that functionality baked in and not have to think about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, it doesn’t lend well to module loaders. This is fine but I want to make builds of it so I can use it in different places and only need to change a few options for each build.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found myself working on separating each of it’s internal tools into files so I can require them into the main file.  This is great as I am learning a lot about module loaders and, specifically, StealJS.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 27</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2015-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 19:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2015-07/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 27&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CanJS and Steal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;canjs-scaffold&quot;&gt;CanJS scaffold&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spun up a project scaffold from scratch for the Code for Cary Art Finder Project.  There isn’t really a good scaffolder for CanJS, unfortunately. There are a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/smarkle/generator-can&quot;&gt;couple&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/package/generator-canjs&quot;&gt;repos&lt;/a&gt; out there with &lt;a href=&quot;http://yeoman.io/&quot;&gt;Yeoman generators&lt;/a&gt; but they are a bit outdated in that they don’t work well with &lt;a href=&quot;http://canjs.com/docs/can.Component.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;can.Component&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  That is to say, they &lt;em&gt;work&lt;/em&gt; they just don’t generate blank components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either way, I thought it would be a good idea to put into practice what I have learned on CanJS project structure.  I’m pretty happy with it and aim to post the project on Github soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to actually keep this structure clean and make &lt;em&gt;it&lt;/em&gt; into a repo that I can use later. I’ve never created a Yeoman generator but I hear they’re super easy. Might take a stab at that as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 26</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2015-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 13:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2015-06/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 26&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PhantomJS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Code for Cary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;phantomjs&quot;&gt;PhantomJS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to research this more, but as I struggle with writing tests for my code, I have this recurring thought: why do we test code in a browser environment that really isn’t an end-user browser?  If it’s a module loader issue, fine. But I suspect it isn’t. Integration tests should be run on the different browsers the project has identified as key browsers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could just be complaining or missing something important. I’m skeptical, though. More research is required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;code-for-cary&quot;&gt;Code for Cary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This past Tuesday (the 10th), Code for Cary met to listen to a request from the Arts Center folks. They essentially want to wrap their artwork database with a useful interface for citizens.  There’s a few different projects by other Brigades doing essentially the same thing but none of them are at the level Cary needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m still going over my notes about the project but I’m really excited to see what we can build for them. Cary, and many many other cities, have beautiful artwork that citizens can enjoy - if only they knew about them or how to find them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 25</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2015-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2015 13:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2015-05/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keeping lists organized&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;keeping-lists-organized&quot;&gt;Keeping lists organized&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using Things a lot in the past few months.  I’ve tried so many To Do apps and methods. I’ll admit that I never dove in the deep end of Getting Things Done. I thought GTD was just too “bossy” for me. I really liked Todo.txt because of its simplicity.  I tried plain pencil and paper but it got too cluttered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After downloading Things, though, I researched GTD more and realized how powerful and simple it really is. Coupled with Things itself, which is very clean and well built, I’ve never had To Do’s so managed and within reach.  To Do lists are different for everyone and there’s so much talk out there about how to manage lists that I won’t go into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to talk about being forced to have multiple lists on different mediums. For example, a client has the project’s tasks in Jira. I have my personal stuff in Things.  My wife puts the shopping list in FetchNotes. I fight the urge to just make everyone use Things. Not that it would do me any good since you can’t really share items in Things…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found that the “inboxing” time is important with keeping this madness under control. I go through my different lists and add what needs adding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s pretty simple and fairly effective. There’s issues with “on-the-fly” situations like shopping lists but I adjust based on the situation. The point is, though, that these situations are minimized.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 24</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2015-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 13:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2015-04/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 24&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Audio notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;audio-notes&quot;&gt;Audio notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought a recorder a while back mostly for personal audio journaling but also for an amature podcast I do with a friend. It feels weird recording yourself, I’m not a scientist or a researcher or a coroner so I don’t really have a &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; for this kind of habit. That is, until I recorded my thoughts when I ran into a difficult programming problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More often then not, there is someone on-line that I can bounce ideas off of at work. But sometimes there isn’t someone available or sometimes I’m not at my computer and I’m just idly thinking of the problem.  It was during one of these moments that I decided to speak my thoughts out loud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s some real power with speaking out your thoughts. It might look a little nutty, but it’s extremely helpful. I’m not sure what this phenomenon is, but it seems like the brain processes the thoughts differently once their out of the realm of thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try it the next time your stuck.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 23</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2015-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 13:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2015-03/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 23&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agile thoughts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Goals for the week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;agile-thoughts&quot;&gt;Agile thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like any method that revolves itself around iteration and self analyzation. Agile is great with these concepts. On the other hand, it doesn’t cease to frustrate how often people try to figure out problems other’s have experienced and solved. I know that every team is different and every project is different, but I don’t agree that teams should spend time figuring out a solved problem as if the problem wasn’t solved already.  I guess what I’m saying is I think teams should recognize there is a problem, which teams seem to do well, and table it until someone (if not everyone on the team) can research the problem some more. Then come back and hash it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;goals-for-the-week&quot;&gt;Goals for the week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suck at git rebase. I don’t understand it, I don’t know what use cases it’s for, etc. I will become more familiar with it this week.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 22</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2015-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2015 20:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2015-02/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 22&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Travel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;travel&quot;&gt;Travel&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been out of town this week for a client and I noticed a few things on this trip that I hadn’t noticed before on previous trips. Specifically to do with the flight itself.  I heard about “man-spreading” on trains the other day. I was a little perturbed at how this isn’t a rule on planes, too. Ugh. &lt;/soapbox&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a standing desk at home and it feels great to stand all day. When I’m traveling, I’ve noticed that I spend a lot more time sitting because most places default to sitting environments - and rightly so, this is how most people work. Still, I am wondering if it’s possible to take a small portable standing desk with me next time. And if so, I wonder if it’s possible to not look like a weirdo when you bust out your folding standing desk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve started creating a wish list in Amazon that contain things that I’ve found are great for traveling. A portable surge protector with built in USB ports, for example. We’ll see how it evolves as I continue to travel.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 21</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2015-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2015 06:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2015-01/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 20&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Metalsmith&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Goals for the week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;metalsmith&quot;&gt;Metalsmith&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.metalsmith.io/&quot;&gt;Metalsmith&lt;/a&gt; is a JavaScript static site generator. The site also says it can scaffold and automate processes. It’s very similar to Gulp in that it uses pipes (called &lt;code&gt;use&lt;/code&gt; in Metalsmith) and, obviously, it uses streams. Metalsmith can indeed be used to scaffold applications but I don’t know why anyone would use that in client work with more heavy communities like Gulp and Grunt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, I tried using Gulp to build a static site and found it somewhat cumbersome and difficult.  Metalsmith seems to handle this task effortlessly.  I’m using it now to build a really simple photoblog site and I find it more flexible than Wintersmith as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wintersmith’s biggest downfall, with me at least, was it’s inability to handle drafts. A plugin would have to be written in order to handle it. Metalsmith is the same. The difference, though, is that writing a plugin for Metalsmith is sooo much easier. That and there’s already a plugin to handle drafts! ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve run into a few problems with Metalsmith because of the way I want to do things, and all I have to do is write a plugin for it. I wanted to change the date format and couldn’t find an easy plugin for that, so I wrote a quick plugin that copies and formats the date. It’s not a very good, reusable plugin, but it does the job for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only weird issue I’ve run into that doesn’t rub me right is pagination of posts. I don’t want to use Handlebars and I’m trying to figure out how to paginate without switching my templating engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, the pagination and custom link plugins are very order dependent. But, that kinda makes sense, I think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;goals-for-the-week&quot;&gt;Goals for the week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am using Things to manage my Todo lists. I added all my little sites as tags and created a Website project. I am populating it with all the updates I want to make to my sites.  This week, I would like to start whittling the list down.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 20</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 21:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-20/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 20&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Catching Up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being mobile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Goals for the week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;catching-up&quot;&gt;Catching Up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technically, this is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; week 20, I am not interested in calculating what week it &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; is. We fail, we get back up and clear the dust, and we keep moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life has continued to move in the past few months. I attended a CanJS meetup, I hope to be able to help out more often with the meetup.  I’m working on building something useful for my wife to help with her homeschooling. Work itself is proving to be fun, hard, and rewarding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;being-mobile&quot;&gt;Being mobile&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have spent the past couple weeks with family in California. The biggest problem I’ve run into is not having ready access to wireless internet (Seriously, who doesn’t have Wi-fi anymore!?) I resolved this using my wireless hotspot which works great! Except I still like to watch things on Hulu and Netflix and sync my Dropbox and update the apps on my phone, etc. These activities have forced me to up our data limit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than internet access, the only other problem is finding a quiet place to work. Coffee joints here aren’t too abundant and the kids can be, well, loud.  Next time I need to travel like this, I’ll probably scope out some coworking offices before hand.  It will probably be cheaper and less stressful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;goals-for-the-week&quot;&gt;Goals for the week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m catching up on all my little web homes. This week’s goal is to simple update all my sites with one item. This could be an article or something simpler.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 19</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-19/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 19&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Cary Updates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Goals for the week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-cary-updates&quot;&gt;The Cary Updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see the main updates on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codeforcary.org/projects/the_cary/updates/2&quot;&gt;Code for Cary&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like the idea of abstracting the scraper tool from the scraping steps.  The page we scrape can change over time and may not lend itself to being scraped easily. Also, we might need to scrape other pages to verify our data.  For these reasons I want to build a tool that can read a configuration file, process it into commands, then do the actual scrape. The file will also tell the tool how to build the data it scrapes.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I need to work out the structure of the config file so I know what needs to be built but I’m thinking of starting small and just trying to make something basic. Then, as I continue with The Cary, I can refactor as needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;goals-for-the-week&quot;&gt;Goals for the week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m in training in Chicago all week so just focusing on absorbing as much as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 18</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2014 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-18/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 18&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Never stop learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CanJS and Firebase&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Goals for the week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;never-stop-learning&quot;&gt;Never stop learning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was watching ‘3 Days to Kill’ the other night. I’m a huge Luc Besson fan, ever since Leon (more widely known as ‘The Professional’).  3 Days to Kill was ok, it was entertaining. It has &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt; to do with web development but there was a moment in the film that gave me pause regarding the progression of experiences and wisdom in our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a scene where Kevin Costner’s character is feeling really bad for himself, sitting on a bridge in Paris, eating Chinese food by himself.  I thought, here’s this bad ass CIA guy who thought he had a solid grasp of his world. But in this moment, he knows nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I like about this movie is that it goes against the cliche, “You can’t teach an old dog new tricks”.  Obviously, we get a happy ending for Kevin Costner after he learned to reassess what really was important in his life.  There is a more important message being displayed which is, family is the most important thing. But let’s focus on the Old-dog-learns-new-trick aspect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the technology world, the most important skill to have is learning. Apparently, this goes double for professional hit-men/CIA/secret agent dads.  But for people working with technology, there are moments where I get frustrated that I have to learn something new (it feels like very week these days). But once this new thing is learned and understood, I feel like He-man branding his sword high in the air; powerful and ready for the next challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;canjs-and-firebase&quot;&gt;CanJS and Firebase&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After building that quick CanJS page last week, I thought I’d take it a step further and build a CMS using Firebase as the backend.  I previously had trouble getting CanJS to talk with Firebase using &lt;code&gt;can.Model&lt;/code&gt;. After a few weeks of working at Bitovi and facing the different CanJS challenges, as well as reviewing the CanJS documentation, I was able to figure out a solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There aren’t any editing capabilities but the exciting part is it took me less than a day to build what I have so far. The next step is getting the live binding in CanJS to auto update the local Firebase data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;goals-for-the-week&quot;&gt;Goals for the week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wasn’t able to spend a lot of time with Document JS, pretty much only what I need for work.  I figured this will be an ongoing thing, learning Document JS as well as our other open source projects, specifically StealJS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connect live binding to Firebase&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write article on experience with CanJS + Firebase.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 17</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2014 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-17/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 17&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changing routines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning Can JS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Goals for the week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;changing-routines&quot;&gt;Changing routines&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I liked finishing my weeks with weeknotes. I noticed that I started Monday with little context and wondered if weeknotes could help with that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d like to be able to start my week with some goals that come from these. I normally have a small list of goals for the week but that usually includes house to-do’s and work to-do’s, not skill-leveling-up to-do’s.  So, I thought I’d try switching my week notes to Mondays instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with changing your routine, though, is that it breaks your routine!  Monday morning I was struggling with trying to remember something I had to do that day. I didn’t remember what it was until late that night.  That alone is a great learning experience: try not to change your routine, if you really have to, set yourself up for success by creating reminders or something similar that will help you transition and rebuild that routine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;learning-canjs&quot;&gt;Learning CANJS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first two weeks at &lt;a href=&quot;http://bitovi.com/&quot;&gt;Bitovi&lt;/a&gt; have been two weeks of non-stop learning. It’s been great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, I decided that I had enough confidence to try something simple with &lt;a href=&quot;http://canjs.com/&quot;&gt;CanJS&lt;/a&gt;. So, I created a very simple display of data using components.  I am going to clean out some of my personal data from it and make the code a bit more generic. Once that’s done, I’ll push the repo and write up a post of what I did. It’s nothing profound but it helped me review what I’ve learned and cement a lot of the concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;goals-for-the-week&quot;&gt;Goals for the week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Push update to my CanJS practice app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.javascriptmvc.com/docs/DocumentJS.html&quot;&gt;DocumentJS&lt;/a&gt;, our open source JavaScript project documentation builder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documentation is a pet-peeve of mine. Its a great opportunity to contribute to a project that can help other’s build helpful documentation for their projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 16</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 23:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-16/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 16&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First week completed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;first-week-completed&quot;&gt;First week completed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Change is sometimes difficult, but always enriching.  This first week at Bitovi has been amazing. My brain hurts… but in a good way. I consider myself a pretty smart fellow; I don’t have a ton of experience but I learn quickly… &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week, though, challenged my ability to learn. The last time I felt this challenged was when I took my first web application development position. It’s so different and complex that it took me a while to get caught up.  On the one hand, I have this level of challenging work and very experienced peers.  On the other hand, I have this gratifying feeling of learning new things and becoming a better engineer.  And just like before, it will take me some time to get caught up, but when I do, it will be glorious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Change can be so difficult that it can cause feelings of insecurity and fear.  This, in turn, increases the risk of failure.  Now imagine a place that understands this dynamic and does everything it can to make sure that people feel welcome and free to express their difficulties.  That’s Bitovi, a place with Bitovians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, change can be and usually is hard but when you’re surrounded by good people that care and want each other to succeed, the only way to fail is to stop trying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s great to be a Bitovian.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 15</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-15/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 15&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last Day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scraping with Cheerio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MongoDB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;last-day&quot;&gt;Last Day&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finished my last day at KSS.  Good times there. It’s always sad to end a relationship.  I still would like to maintain the individual relationships I made and even the organizational relationship as well. What I’m trying to say is that the relationship that I had between myself and the employer is done and &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; makes me feel a little bummed out. You spend all this time building relationships with people and the work itself and then &lt;em&gt;bam&lt;/em&gt;, it’s done.  It’s easy to maintain a connection when you have to be at a place doing a specific list of tasks. Without that constraint, keeping those relationships is difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, the end of one chapter leads to the start of another. New people, new challenges, new puzzles. Can’t wait.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;scraping-with-cheerio&quot;&gt;Scraping with Cheerio&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Town of Cary maintains a historic theater named &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.townofcary.org/Departments/Parks__Recreation___Cultural_Resources/Facilities/Cultural_Arts_Centers/thecary.htm&quot;&gt;The Cary&lt;/a&gt;.  The town also maintains it’s website that lists all the show times.  Apparently, they don’t do a great job of using the data to it’s fullest potential.  The Code for America brigade that I help out at wants to parse out that data and create a front end experience that is more helpful to potential customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started with figuring out how to scrape a page with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cheeriojs/cheerio&quot;&gt;Cheerio&lt;/a&gt;. It’s amazingly easier than I thought it would be.  The problem is with the structure of the page.  As I’m building the scraping module, I’m hoping that they don’t change the structure very often, if at all.  Without unique attributes to target specific elements, I have to use the structure to find the show time listings on the page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The show times themselves have a very volatile structure. So, I’m trying to use tools like Moment to figure out what cell has what piece of data.  That’s where I am at right now.  All of this is in a prototyping stage but I also want to start storing the raw scrapes somewhere… somewhere being MongoDB.  The more data points I have, the more accurate my parser will be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;mongodb&quot;&gt;MongoDB&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are so many technologies out there. NoSQL data storage tools alone are a handful.  I just got a new machine and I’ve decided that instead of installing every tool I want to learn or use on the computer itself, I will spin up a VirtualBox machine and install it on there instead.  It’s a little bit of an overhead as far as installing and using go but the ability to completely turn off a service is worth it to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MongoDB, for example, I &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; will not be taking up system resources when the VirtualBox machine is turned off.  Let’s say I need to install MySQL or something similar. I can do the same thing for those.  Development of the application still happens on my machine, they just point to the correct IP/Port to access the service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having never used Mongo, I’m looking over the documentation on how to do basic save/edits to data. Found a tool called Mongoose for NodeJS. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 14</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2014 23:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-14/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 14&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New Job&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-job&quot;&gt;New Job&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of my “web developer” time has been spent working on products or for a very specific set of customers.  I tried freelance in the beginning but didn’t have the experience for it at the time.  So, to have the opportunity to not just get some of that “agency” experience but to also work with a company that mirrors my own ideals as far as open source, tools, and community - well, it’s an amazing feeling.  My last day with Knowledge Sharing Systems is the the 12th.  I start with Bitovi as soon as I can. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find that transitions are awkward and weird.  Sometimes you get what people in the military call “figmo” (eff it, got my orders) and you just stop caring.  I have to be honest, I do feel like that in some ways which, in turn, makes me feel horrible.  I &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to care.  I &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; the thing that I create to be its very best.  So, I pondered my feelings for a while and realized something important: we owe our amazing jobs to the people that use the things we make.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, duh, right? I gave it some more thought, though… I get to build web things because there is a need for them; because there is a demand.  Due to that demand, I have amazing opportunites available to me that I wouldn’t have access to otherwise.  It’s these people that I want to honor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yea, it’s a pretty mushy but it is true.  All I’m saying is, if the work sucks, fine. But don’t stop giving it 100% just because it sucks - it’s being built because people have a need for it and they deserve your best. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a lot of fun at my job, lot’s of interesting, fun, and challenging puzzles.  I’m just ready to move on to the next set of challenges, I think.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 13</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30  Aug 2014 08:24:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-13/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 13&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perfomance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CanJS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;perfomance&quot;&gt;Perfomance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of performant JavaScript is not a dormant subject nor an unexplored one.  I run into things all the time that teach me how to write faster JavaScript. The problem I found out recently, though, is that the tips I find are usually tips on how current code can be faster. Like looping through an array backwards (from length to zero) or using arrays to concatenate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not having a computer science degree (and I’m not really certain the two are linked, but it sure feels like they are), I had not heard of Big O notation before.  But this is the kind of stuff I want to learn when it comes to writing better JavaScript.  When it comes to writing code, I try to focus on making it readable along with making it fast and making it the right solution. Striking a balance between these is difficult as it is. Arriving to the balanced solution is increasingly difficult when training on one or many of the different parts is absent. For me, for example, I obviously suck at performant JavaScript. I think I do pretty good with making it readable. Research, tests and other reviews will tell me if the solution is correct - so that’s pretty good too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point is, though, as our skills continuously evolve, we’ll unlock discoveries and knowledge that allow us to continue improving.  It’s like a skills tree in a video game, you can’t unlock some parts of the tree without first unlocking other parts. But with every unlocked skill, we get that much better in a fight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;canjs&quot;&gt;CanJS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I visited my wife at work last week and noticed that they were using this big binder to keep track of their schedules. I examined some of the sheets and found hand written corrections and notes.  I wondered how could they possibly not experience situations where people arrive to work at the wrong times… or days?! I thought I could help out by working on a scheduling app using Firebase and CanJS.  Two tools I’ve been itching to really commit to for a while now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chose CanJS a while ago because of it’s small foot print.  After working with it (and after working with Ember a month ago), I’m still pretty happy with CanJS.  It’s pretty straight forward, although I think that some of the training materials are outdated.  The documentation helps with this as it’s easy to read and very concise.  I’ll add more updates as I go along.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Warriors</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/Warriors%20of%20the%20Code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24  Aug 2014 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/Warriors%20of%20the%20Code/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warriors of the Code&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are the Warriors of the Code. We are dedicated, strong, merry, and in search of glory. Often we find ourselves engaged in such glorious battles. It is in these battles that warriors fall, advances hard fought, and the days long and tiring.  But we are destroyers and carpenters! We hunger for challenges. We thirst for knowledge! Victory and glory is assured for those that follow the elite, the Warriors of the Code!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today is the 28th of July. I fear how difficult this will be to write just before the day my friend passed away, but I need to write this; it needs to be a thing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s ironic that I write this in Sublime - he defended it’s strengths to me. The lighting is dark in my room except for a white light above my desk, the perfect amount of light for working at night, really. All things on my desk perfectly visible, notes scribbled on index cards, scattered across my desk; this morning’s empty mug of coffee; and a notebook opened to a page with the words “Warrior of the Code”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Years ago, he would leave his desk for a meeting or go grab something to eat or go speak with one of our analysts. Every time, he left his computer unlocked. Little horns would slowly peek out from the crown of my head as I snuck over to his cubicle. The actions of my trademark prank were down to a muscle reflex - I would activate the impaired vision theme in Windows and lower the resolution of his monitors, then run like hell.  Upon his return, I struggled to keep a straight face, sometimes I gave myself away and we would laugh. Other times he would wake his computer and we would laugh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those were &lt;strong&gt;good times.&lt;/strong&gt; He was such a good sport about it all. The conversations we would have on best practices, relationships, race, life… the future. Always that grin on his face and always a baseball cap covering his dome. &lt;em&gt;Always&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His viewing was surreal. My mind battled the truth that my senses explained. That person lying there? He wasn’t smiling but it &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; him. I knew that he was gone and so were the smiles. So were all the thoughtful and frank discussions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There lay my friend’s empty shell. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Warrior of the Code, though, for all eternity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quote in the beginning was written a year ago.  The Warriors of the Code was created the week after he died, if only in my heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of me fears the status of his everlasting soul. Part of me is angry - he had no right to take away his potential from the world he was born into. Part of me is content knowing that I was his friend, even for just a sample of the time he lived.  Every part of me, though, believes that he lived with such passion and direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He loved his music. He loved the web.  Both things he did with all of his energy.  One of our last deep conversations he said something that has never left me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“… You can go where the legacy is and be part of something great or you can stay where you are, create your own legacy &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;make&lt;/em&gt; something great.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I argued with him. Sometimes you &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to move on. Sometimes you &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; something new. We agreed on one thing though, it is up to you to create your own legacy, to make something great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day he was buried, I promised myself to live what I always knew was right.  I would create my own legacy and I would make something great. For me first, but in part for my friend as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two years ago today, my friend made his final choice - he left us what he could and took the rest with him.  But what he left the people around him isn’t worthless or frivolous; he left us the best part of himself.  That smile of his, that energy - his spirit!  It’s that spirit that I fall back to on difficult days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daniel Walker was a good man. I called him my friend. I miss him. You should, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depression, mental health, and suicide are important subjects. One that I feel our country does not take seriously at all.  Please make yourself aware of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.suicidepreventionlifeline.org/&quot;&gt;warning signs&lt;/a&gt;. If you are considering suicide, please call 1-800-273-8255. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 12</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23  Aug 2014 08:24:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-12/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Word Problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wakanda 9&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;word-problems&quot;&gt;Word Problems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was given a programming word problem to solve this week.  It has been a &lt;em&gt;long&lt;/em&gt; time since I have worked on word problems, let alone a programming specific one.  The problem used typical programming problem tropes, yet I found myself doing a good deal of research to solve. It was exciting to be challenged that way - it’s been a while. I hope to have a dedicated article on it later next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;wakanda-9&quot;&gt;Wakanda 9&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week was end of sprint so I was focused on that much of the week.  We’re taking a week off to catch up on admin stuff, work on some prototyping, and explore Wakanda 9. At first, we were thinking of implementing it straight out, but after a little research, we realized it wasn’t an actual release; it was in their “stabilization channel”.  I’m not sure what that means, but they also have a “production channel” which is still pointing to Wakanda 8. Because of this, we assumed that Wakanda 9 is a release candidate at best, a beta product at worst. Either way, not ready for production yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wakanda 9 removed a lot of deprecated stuff. Stuff that we were using because of Wakanda’s poor documentation. For example, I tried using the newer data storage events but couldn’t get them to work. I then flipped over to the deprecated versions and they worked perfectly. The documentation is confusing and poorly written, unfortunately. We often have to bring out the hammer to get things to work. This is bad for obvious reasons, but it’s also a good thing.  It is a good thing because it’s an &lt;em&gt;awesome&lt;/em&gt; way to learn.  Having to pave your own way, without a guide or a map? It’s exploration at it’s purest!  That doesn’t mean I think it’s an efficient way, I just think it’s fun sometimes. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Meetup Presentation</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/Meetup-talk-aar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16  Aug 2014 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/Meetup-talk-aar/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;first-meetup-presentation-after-action-review&quot;&gt;First Meetup Presentation After Action Review&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first heard of an AAR (&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/After-action_review&quot;&gt;After Action Review&lt;/a&gt; ) from my wife while she was in the Army. Years later, I joined a team that used the Agile method and became accustomed to sprint retrospectives.  I like the retrospective concept as a method of reviewing the self and the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve said before that this journal’s purpose is partially to help me improve and learn. I meet a lot of people that are afraid to voice their thoughts for fear of being wrong and coming off as a fool. I am one such person. But I never feel that people expressing their thoughts, no matter how raw that thought is, that they themselves are fools. It takes strength and courage to put yourself out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In these situations, though, one needs to look critically at one’s performance and be brutally honest in order to improve.  I hesitated for a moment about putting my thoughts on the Meetup, I’m pretty embarrassed about my performance.  I then remembered the spiel I give to many people about learning web design and development, failure is growth! I immediately decided that I need to be candid about my feelings, thoughts, and decisions regarding my presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am using the format I found on Wikipedia for AAR. They use slightly better verbiage than I would have used. :) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;grunt-gulp-meetup-aar&quot;&gt;Grunt/Gulp Meetup AAR&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok. Here we go… :D  Most of these are my own opinions, many people said it was good (which was very kind of them to say, but I think they were being TOO kind. Thanks to all who said so, though. I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; appreciate the kindness!).  I could be off on some of this stuff… but I really doubt it. ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-was-supposed-to-happen&quot;&gt;What was supposed to happen&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had slides with examples and some step-by-step processes for learning and using Grunt and Gulp.  I was supposed to run through the slides, use my notes for help (if needed), and run through the examples in between some of the slides.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The slides and my speech would help guide attendees attention from one concept to the next. With each slide, we were to build on the previous concept, ultimately working up to an automation task using Gulp and Grunt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On some slides, I had queues that would tell me when to flip over to command line or Sublime (text editor) to go over the examples.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At the end of the slides, I would go over any more examples and questions the audience had.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-happened&quot;&gt;What happened&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I set up the PC to display in extended mode. The slideshow on the project and my notes on my screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I started off OK. Jumped straight into the slides was doing fine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The extended mode caught me off guard, I practiced using one monitor so I assumed everyone could see what I was seeing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I could gauge the audience’s response to some things I would say. I saw blank stares, confused stares, or bored stares.  I tried to adapt to this by trying to explain some extra detail of whatever concept I was explaining at the time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I got ahead of my slides when going through some command line code - before I had set up the concepts for the step I had mistakenly moved on to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I remembered &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; of my queues to flip over to a different application, not all of them. I stammered when this happened.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The text from command line, Sublime, and Far were too small on the projector.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I digressed… A LOT.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I explained a concept and moved on to the next… abruptly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I felt like I struggled explaining the concepts even though I understand them and use them all the time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was flipping between a command prompt (which I did not intend to use), Far Manager, and Sublime… a LOT.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There was a storm that knocked out the power momentarily. At this point, I switched to mirrored mode for the display.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The overall theme of the presentation changed as we went along, making it unclear and confusing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s probably a lot more but it all falls under the same stuff above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-are-some-improves&quot;&gt;What are some improves&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practice explaining the core concepts before even working on the slides.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write the entire presentation as a blog article first. I get my thoughts out better in writing, so an article should be the start of the presentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I practiced by myself, maybe practice in front of people? Like friends, perhaps?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I practiced the transitions from slides to text editor, but it was not in a “live” mentality; I would say to myself “and switch to sublime here”… instead of actually doing it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have queues that tell me to flip BACK to the slides.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practice the examples more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I actually volunteered to do just Gulp. It was recommended to do Gulp &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; Grunt. This was a great idea, but I am not familiar with Grunt like I am with Gulp. I should have agreed but asked to do my talk in two months instead of the one. This would have given me more time to become familiar with Grunt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practice. Practice. PRACTICE…. THEN PRACTICE AGAIN.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-are-some-sustains&quot;&gt;What are some sustains&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m having trouble with this section…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Um… I think I had pretty good eye contact?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think that I know my tools pretty well. I was nervous, but I know how to use Sublime and command line.  I didn’t hesitate with those except when I couldn’t see the result during the time I was using “mirrored” mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I feel like I gave honest answers to audience questions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don’t take myself too seriously in public, which, I hope, makes people feel more comfortable. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-can-i-do-differently-next-time&quot;&gt;What can I do differently next time&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be honest about an achievable time line.  This I had to learn. I don’t think I could have known that I would not have been able to become familiar with Grunt in that time.  But, now I do.  So, next time, be frank about needing more time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practice. EVERY. DAMNED. DAY.  I think I practiced a lot, but I made changes with almost every run through. I wonder if part of my problem was that I should have gotten to the point where changes were minute or nonexistent before I could say I was actually &lt;em&gt;practicing&lt;/em&gt;.  Either way, I think practice would have made this go way more smoothly as I can just run through things instinctively without having to think hard about my next step.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practice with an 800*600 screen, make sure anything I am going to display (especially if it has text) that it is bumped up to as large as possible, so everyone can see.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use black on white text? I think projectors with poor lighting display this better. Command line, Sublime, and Far all had dark backgrounds and white text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t use an “extended” display mode. Stick to mirrored!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a basic slide and example ready &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; volunteering for a meetup.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Invite friends over for dinner, then sucker them into listening/watching my practice. :D&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Record myself during practice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Record myself during actual presentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-thoughts&quot;&gt;Final thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, it sounds like I’m saying I didn’t practice enough. Seems legit.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A while back, I went to a meetup where the speaker was, well, not that great.  As I thought this, though, I immediately thought that this person is up there giving a talk… which is more than I have done.  A friendly person echoed that statement to me right after I finished and it raised my spirits. Sure, I sucked, but I did it. I finished. And, by gum, I’ll improve!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also wanted to note that everyone’s general friendliness is another reason why I am excited to be a web developer. Nothing but encouragement from people - it’s a great feeling to have supportive peers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 11</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16  Aug 2014 08:24:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-11/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grunt/Gulp Talk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consolidated sites to Digital Ocean&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explored Laddr&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;grunt-gulp-talk&quot;&gt;Grunt/Gulp Talk&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did my talk. If I measured the success of a talk in that I didn’t run out in fear and didn’t get “boo’d” off the “stage”… then I succeeded!  It was hard for me to gage if the audience understood the concepts I was trying to present.  A lot of people did, I got this just from talking with them. Some, people, I could see, were struggling.  I take that as a personal failing and it inspired me to write a After Action Review. I’ll post that up later today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;consolidated-sites-to-digital-ocean&quot;&gt;Consolidated sites to Digital Ocean&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital Ocean doesn’t have redundancies and, so far, they seem to have issues more often than not. It is marketed as a developer VPS solution, which, to me, says stability is not to be expected. And you know what? That’s ok. It’s good enough and it is insanely cheap.  The sites that I put on there aren’t popular even by any definition, so if they go down even for a few hours here and there, it should be fine.  If they grow in popularity (ha! Right…) then it will make more sense to move them over to something else. Maybe AWS or A Small Orange (they have a similar plan at $20 but with redundant hardware, for example).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital Ocean has a ton of great guides for installing all sorts of things. Ghost 0.5 was just released so they are missing the updated version number, but the process is the same. I learned how to have multiple Ghost instances running under one NginX server and how to configure them all as services. I &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; their “droplet” interface as well. Even with having to use command line for the server itself, their interface is so much easier to use then cPanel (I was told that you can install a GUI and use that to admin the server, but I’m starting to like command line!). Here’s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitalocean.com/?refcode=ef003a64b58d&quot;&gt;referral sign up link&lt;/a&gt; if you’re interested, which you should be. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;explored-laddr&quot;&gt;Explored Laddr&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laddr is nifty PHP app that helps Code for America Brigades keep track of their projects, conversations, and other stuff. It was created as a Code for America project (I think?) in Philadelphia.  As I said before, I’m helping out with the Cary Brigade and the first area I’m helping out with is the front end to the Brigade’s website.  Laddr is commonly placed on the root domain for many Brigades. We’re not set up for that now but we might in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m curious how Laddr and Github will mesh as far as communication on bugs and features.  The administration page is nifty. I can edit the PHP templating and other code easily through this back end page. I’ll get to really dig in this weekend and I’m super exited.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 10</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10  Aug 2014 08:24:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-10/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Missed my Friday deadline&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grunt/Gulp Talk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meditation and rest&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;missed-my-friday-deadline&quot;&gt;Missed my Friday deadline&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to have these written by Friday night, just as a personal goal. I’m a little stressed out on my first talk next week, but I’ll get to that.  I feel like it’s ok to miss deadlines from time to time, provided that it isn’t a common occurrence. The problem, I think, we run into when we’re late on something is trying to get caught up.  We’re so busy that falling behind on one thing puts everything else behind as well. That’s why it’s important to build a buffer or… wait for it… a graceful fallback! :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At work, we have periodic “non-sprints” where we aren’t in a sprint and aren’t expected to complete story points.  We can work the backlog or do some research on backlog items.  I’m no agile expert, so I don’t know how close this follows the agile method or if the terms are correct. Anyway, I think that in anything we do, it’s important to be able to do one of two things (or both, really): claim to do bankruptcy or have a non-work week.  I’m not behind on my personal projects… or work projects for that matter, but being late for my weeknotes made me think about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;grunt-gulp-talk&quot;&gt;Grunt/Gulp Talk&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m practicing my talk for this Tuesday the 12th.  I’m psyched. I’m nervous. I want to get back to Code for Cary so I’m excited for two reasons. Being able to share my thoughts on Gulp/Grunt/automation, but also be able to redirect my attention to other things. Being my first talk, I’ve given this &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of attention. I’m not complaining, it’s just the fact of the past few weeks. Anyway, I’m planning on throwing the talk and all my materials, including articles I researched for the talk, on github.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;meditation-and-rest&quot;&gt;Meditation and rest&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with being able to take a non-work work week or being able to claim task bankruptcy, it’s also important to have complete non-work time.  Along with doing mind dumps, I have started doing meditation and introspection time.  Straight up sleep is still a work in progress but it’s high priority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned meditation in an Aikido class I took a long time ago and I liked the peace and tranquility I got from it. It’s a struggle trying to keep your mind clear, but it’s a good healthy struggle.  Keeping balance in your mind is like a muscle that one needs to exercise in order for it to work efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once my mind is clear (ish… I still can’t really achieve complete calmness), I will do a mind dump.  I just write down every thought that comes back. Some thoughts are “to dos”, some are ideas, and some are personal introspections.  It’s these personal thoughts that I am going for. Understanding why I think things or why I have problems in certain parts of my life are very important to self improvement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does this have to do with software? Software engineering is problem solving. Problem solving is a muscle, too.  It requires higher reasoning and a balanced mind, in my opinion, which some people have inherently, or, like me, have to work hard at it.  I found that meditation and introspection help improve your ability to focus and problem solve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also makes you feel better. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 9</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01  Aug 2014 10:24:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-09/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 9&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grunt/Gulp Talk is a go&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installed Ubuntu server on old netbook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Playing with Yo API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;grunt-gulp-talk-is-a-go&quot;&gt;Grunt/Gulp Talk is a go&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m struggling with what my actual goal is. In researching the topic, I realized it is actually fairly easy to learn how to use both Gulp and Grunt. The problem is first understanding the concepts of tasks and NPM and dependencies.  The other problem I feel web craftsfolk face is trying to stay in sync with the available toolset without losing momentum in other things like life etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have two choices then. Take this talk with the literal “Gulp and Grunt” description and just discuss the differences. Or, I can use this as a vehicle to show how important it is to take that first step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suppose I could do both. :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;installed-ubuntu-server-on-old-netbook&quot;&gt;Installed Ubuntu server on old netbook&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has been on the back burner for a while. I have wanted a portable web server for a while now. My netbook isn’t used for much these days except as a print server.  After bringing up a server through Digital Ocean, I realized I could have done the netbook first as a learning experience.  Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t expect to have so much fun with this.  That feeling when something works, almost like the atypical comic book regular person discovering they have a super power that can help the world.  I can use it to test APIs, work as a staging server, or serve local pages for home stuff. In order to do this, though, I am saying that it is no longer a computer; it is strictly my server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;playing-with-yo-api&quot;&gt;Playing with Yo API&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the tests I used while playing with the web server was playing with the Yo API. There’s not much to it but I thought I could use it on the web server to check my main server and “Yo” me when the main server is out.  I thought it would be fun to publicize a Yo address that updated a website with people that have Yo’d that address. The point is, it’s a toy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 8</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 10:24:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-08/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 8&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created Wakanda data import tool&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Started work on Gulp/Grunt talk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up Ember environment with Yeoman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;created-wakanda-data-import-tool&quot;&gt;Created Wakanda data import tool&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t find a way to easily import data from one server to another that was required by parts of the application. &lt;a href=&quot;http://dev.endgamestudio.com/Wakanda-Import-Concept/&quot;&gt;I created a datastore class method&lt;/a&gt; the read a JSON file and import any missing records.  It’s a great first step for our team if we decide to continue using Wakanda local datastores (versus remote datastores).  I think that these local datastores are great, faster, less cumbersome, and more powerful. But that’s not my call. :(&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;started-gulp-grunt-talk&quot;&gt;Started Gulp/Grunt talk&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finished my outline and now in the process of adding more and more detail. Still nothing to link to yet which is good. I feel that it’s not a &lt;em&gt;thing&lt;/em&gt; until there is a link which keeps my nerves in check.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;set-up-ember-environment-with-yeoman&quot;&gt;Set up Ember environment with Yeoman&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I freak out at the shear amount of &lt;em&gt;stuff&lt;/em&gt; Yeoman loads in a folder after it is done running a generator. The Grunt file alone is insane. Once I looked through it, though, it made sense. The same goes for the rest of the objects in the project folder. Anyway, I loaded up an Ember generator to use EmberFire on it.  Get to fiddle with that tonight actually.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wakanda Data Import</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/Wakanda-Import-Concept/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 10:01:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/Wakanda-Import-Concept/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;wakanda-data-import-tool&quot;&gt;Wakanda Data Import Tool&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When new data is created to support the application, not user data, we need a way to update servers down the deployment chain.  With SQL, this was easy… ish. A versioned query that was part of the deployment handled the task.  With Wakanda, we could do the same thing. &lt;em&gt;OR&lt;/em&gt; we could take a step higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was tasked with creating a bare bones rights engine for our app. In it, I had to display error messages to the user. I don’t like hardcoding messages, I prefer to let the client edit them whenever possible.  I created the solution for this but then ran into a problem syncing data across development and test servers - which meant we were going to run into a problem syncing the data to production… once we reached that point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I created a &lt;a href=&quot;http://doc.wakanda.org/Datastore-Model-Designer/Datastore-Class-Methods.300-473312.en.html&quot;&gt;Datastore class method&lt;/a&gt; that checked for a JSON file and imported any required data into the target datastore. It worked great. A couple of issues did come up like exposing the method to the client and abstracting the schema of the table from the import process. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having the method exposed to the client is dangerous for many reasons, most importantly being that our team is still new to Wakanda, which is also still in its infancy.  The solution is to be able to call the method from the server itself. Or easily disable the method once the app is in “production” mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The schema part I’m still debating on how to handle. I can include the schema in the import file. I could verify the schema based on the key/value pairs in the data itself.  The main task is complete and was approved so the next time I have to do something similar, I’ll go in and clean it up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;https://gist.github.com/Guamaso/7d80034a24f50eaee1bf.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 7</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2014 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-07/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 7: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wakanda Training&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gulp and Grunt Talk Brief&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fiddling with Firebase&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Signed up for Digital Ocean&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;wakanda-training&quot;&gt;Wakanda Training&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of the week, I attended a two day training at work on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wakanda.org/&quot;&gt;Wakanda&lt;/a&gt;.  The two days reminded me of what they say about Calculus: &lt;em&gt;it’s like 90% Algebra&lt;/em&gt;.  Wakanda training (Wakanda being based on a JavaScript stack) was 90% JavaScript.  It was a good refresh for myself and a very good one-oh-one-esque course for some of our “desktop” developers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sidebar: are they called “desktop” developers? I’ve heard them being referred to as “system language” developers. My point is, they are not web developers by trade.  Writing code for the web can be very different.  Throw in HTML markup and CSS styling and web applications get even tougher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the training was good. It was also good to hang out with the team for a while in RL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;gulp-and-grunt-meetup-talk-brief&quot;&gt;Gulp and Grunt Meetup Talk Brief&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote up the brief, created my main bullet points and started working on the deck itself.  I’m excited but I’m also very nervous. This is an interesting experiment - I don’t do public speaking.  The Dev Journal’s goal was to improve how I learn.  Having to publicize my thoughts forces me to think deeper about what I’m going to say. Doing a public speaking event, even something as humble as a local meetup, seems to be having the same effect but in multiples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I submitted the brief and received a positive note. I’m waiting for the Meetup page to get updated before I put my nose to the grindstone on the presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;fiddling-with-firebase&quot;&gt;Fiddling with Firebase&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I updated the code that feeds a random haiku on my home page. I’m trying to make it so I can link to specific haiku’s I write.  Learning a lot about refactoring and how fun it is to shoot yourself in the foot. :&amp;lt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;signed-up-for-digital-ocean&quot;&gt;Signed up for Digital Ocean&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a web server that runs WordPress but I am not a fan of cPanel. It seems that I have come to prefer command line and direct access to the server. I heard about Digital Ocean from the Wakanda training and immediately purchased a droplet.  For five dollars, I am able to purchase a virtual server with not-so-bad specs.  Once the shared web server is up, I will bump up the specs in order to host WordPress &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; a couple of Ghost instances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m writing up a list of what I did to get going with a droplet. I had about 2 days, cumulative, experience with running Linux through command line. There is a lot to write about from my experience. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 6</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2014 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-06/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 6: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More Meetups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publishing through Wintersmith with Gulp updated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Github question/thought&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;more-meetups&quot;&gt;More Meetups&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I try to go to as many Meetups as I possibly can.  There are many in Durham for topics such as JavaScript and more. Unfortunately, those Meetups are a bit more difficult for me to make consistently.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/designcrop/&quot;&gt;Crop&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/functionpink/&quot;&gt;Function Pink&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/WebDesign2-0/&quot;&gt;Web Design&lt;/a&gt;, and (now) &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Triangle-Code-for-America/&quot;&gt;Code for Cary&lt;/a&gt; I try my hardest to make, wherever they are held.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Triangle-JavaScript/&quot;&gt;Triangle JavaScript&lt;/a&gt; is also a good one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am helping out the Code for Cary brigade which is fun.  I made a comment on my first Meetup with them that there aren’t enough “doing” Meetups, just lots of “conversation” or “presentation” Meetups - which is fine, but we definitely need more “doing” Meetups.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Web Design Meetup asked for presentations and I thought now would be a good time to put up.  I have learned a lot regarding Gulp and I figured doing a presentation is the next step in my progression.  So, I volunteered. I need to create a brief and send it to Pepper and hopefully she and her fellow organizers will like it.  In addition to the existing &lt;a href=&quot;http://dev.endgamestudio.com/articles/project-mind-dump/&quot;&gt;projects I wrote about&lt;/a&gt; the other day, I now have added a presentation to the list. Good times! No sarcasm there, I love this stuff!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;publishing-through-wintersmith-with-gulp&quot;&gt;Publishing through Wintersmith with Gulp&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I updated the script after finally getting Aspell properly installed on my machine.  I’m not sure if I did something wrong during install (I don’t think I did) but the system path wasn’t updated with the Aspell &lt;code&gt;bin&lt;/code&gt; location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With added spell checking support, I also improved the Gulpfile with better handling of articles as they move through my workflow.  I need to clean it up a bit and then update the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/Guamaso/a8717f5085c0728f91c0&quot;&gt;Gulpfile Gist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d also like to make a web interface for it that let’s me edit and process the spell check results in the browser.  Add that to the backlog, I suppose. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;github-thought-question&quot;&gt;Github thought/question&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I work from either &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; or from a branch I create (typically &lt;code&gt;dev&lt;/code&gt;). New versions or releases come as tags.  I don’t see the benefit to keeping versions in their own branch.  New work, fixes, or sandboxes: yes, but not old versions.  This is all raw thought; I haven’t done any research on this yet, so I could be wrong. Still, when I find a repo that uses this, I would expect the most recent version to be set to master, not some version in the middle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found a repo that I needed for work and I noticed that the master branch seemed odd.  The structure didn’t match what I was using in their commercial product.  I submitted an issue without looking through their branches. If I had, I would have found that the stuff I was looking for was in a branch.  I feel like there should have been a &lt;code&gt;readme.md&lt;/code&gt; file to explain their structure and the product itself. I admit, I should have looked through the branches first.  I still think it’s a weird way to structure a repo but it is on me to look before I leap. Lesson learned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, this same repo’s owner left a comment on a prior issue that the project’s bug tracker was elsewhere.  Yet, Github’s issue tracker was on. It just makes me feel like they put stuff on Github to attract attention to the product - which is perfectly fine, but if this is the business plan, ya’ gotta commit 100% (no pun intended). People should create a mental model quickly and with little effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could be wrong on all of this but I doubt I am wrong on everything… just some of it. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project Mind Dump</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/project-mind-dump/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 14:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/project-mind-dump/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I suffer from “Oh shinny” disease. Symptoms include taking on too many new projects, tasks, or challenges.  There is no cure, but symptoms can be alleviated somewhat by sitting down and doing a mind dump.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use mind dumps to get everything out onto something I can organize and prioritize.  In this case, in keeping with the purpose of the Dev Journal, I want to keep myself accountable for what I have taken on.  So, I’m also including a quick status update on the different projects I’ve started within the past couple months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;wordpress-via-yeoman&quot;&gt;WordPress via Yeoman&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I originally wanted to create a simple web app for an data import I am working on.  My first goal was to install WordPress using Yeoman. That worked great. The next goal was to be able to initiate a simple PHP web server for development using the install location as the web root.  This proved difficult due to my limited understanding of the built in PHP web server, MySQL server, and XAMPP.  I did eventually get that to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last goal before actually being able to start working was to understand how to access data within the WordPress tables using nothing but the WordPress API’s (maybe some plugins, if needed). This is where work ceased on this project. I found that my time was better spent learning &lt;a href=&quot;http://emberjs.com/&quot;&gt;Ember.js&lt;/a&gt; and building an app that way.  Still, I would like to establish a good workflow using WordPress. Something that includes a PHP web server, MySQL server, and anything else one would need to work with WordPress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll look to &lt;a href=&quot;http://bower.io/&quot;&gt;Bower&lt;/a&gt; for this and report back… when I can.  This is low priority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;gulp-and-publishing-via-wintersmith&quot;&gt;Gulp and Publishing via Wintersmith&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mentioned before why I’m not a fan of Grunt.  Things like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/substack/stream-handbook&quot;&gt;“streams”&lt;/a&gt; and “vinyl” files confuse me a bit but I still prefer Gulp over Grunt.  Maybe that is due to my style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I worked a good deal on my script that helps publish articles with &lt;a href=&quot;http://wintersmith.io/&quot;&gt;Wintersmith&lt;/a&gt;.  There are two items left on my To Do list, getting the spell check working and more awareness of what articles are &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; published.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is still ongoing and it’s actually very rewarding. I was not aware of streams and it’s a good way to learn more about Node.js.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;code-for-cary-page&quot;&gt;Code for Cary page&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I attended a meetup and offered my assistance with some of their front end problems. I thought the page was great as Robert, the creator of the page and co-captain of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Triangle-Code-for-America/&quot;&gt;Code for Cary brigade&lt;/a&gt;, said he learned how to implement a new script that used a slider affect when the user scrolls the page.  We always focus on whether a page (or product) is good based on the experience for the end user is.  This is a good measure but it’s not the only one.  Learning how to use something and when to apply it is a success. The end user may not like it which is a failure according to that first measure but even that is useful. Failures are only a failure if you don’t learn from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I digress. I’m updating the page and really want to use LESS instead of straight CSS. I’m still working on this as well. This is actually number one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;writing-moar-&quot;&gt;Writing moar…&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like writing. I love it. I suck at it, though.  I suck at web development, too, though.  And this journal’s purpose is to help me learn web development as much as it is to help me learn to write more better. (I did that on purpose…)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I write in a few different places which may contribute to the problem of not writing more often. Although, I don’t feel like three places is a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I write about creativity in one spot, video games in another, and web dev here.  Not too bad.  My goal is one article a month for each site. With as many minor posts as possible. This, in case you were wondering, is a minor post. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really just need to shut up and write more. This is an ongoing thing, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;mentoring&quot;&gt;Mentoring&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like I said, I’m not that great. I don’t have my own agency, I haven’t organized my own conference, or made any major contributions to the community really.  I made peace with my inability to keep up with others skill-wise.  I know the saying, there is always someone smarter than you, but that’s not what this is about. I’m ok with not being an expert at anything.  That doesn’t mean stop learning or trying my best, it just means that I measure my success against myself. I know what I am capable of now and I know what success looks like to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Success looks like helping others develop their skills and confidence.  I meet a lot of people just entering the field with that deer-in-headlights look. They want to know where to start and they’re scared because nothing makes sense.  Been there. I remember it clearly.  I remember thinking how much I would benefit from a mentor.  There are plenty of places to ask questions and get guidance on-line, but let’s be honest, we can be a bunch of jerks sometimes.  I’m getting rant-y so I’ll just finish by saying that we need a better mentoring system.  One that doesn’t require an initiate to have loads of cash (as much as those programs are worth the investment, not everyone has the time or finances to apply).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m doing research on how I can help.  Again, I’m not one of the “greats” by any means, but I got &lt;em&gt;heart&lt;/em&gt;, yo.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week Notes 5</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2014 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-05/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Week Notes #5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Establishing a LESS workflow using Gulp. Found out about Code for America - a really cool thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of leveling up my skills is also leveling up my ability to communicate, lead, and mentor others. I feel that these skills require constant interaction with fellow developers.  Therefore, I attend a lot of meetups… well, as many as I can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://codeforamerica.org/&quot;&gt;Code for America&lt;/a&gt; is a really great organization. Having developed an interest in local government while working for the City of Fayetteville a few years back, I thought it would be interesting to see what the organization had to offer.  There are three Brigades (groups or teams), in the Raleigh/Durham area: Raleigh, Durham, and Cary. It so happened that I was free the night of the Cary meetup.  Meeting with the team of civic-minded folks was great and inspiring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They mentioned needing help with the landing page of the Code for Cary site. I started working on that earlier and thought it would be a great place to learn LESS. Unfortunately, I am a perfectionist.  Through my initial research, I found that using LESS in development requires adding scripts so the files are compiled by the client. This is fine - actually, this is perfect. The problem is, I don’t know what the production environment is like. Which means that I’ll have to compile a build and have that ready for production. That is just too much for a simple page site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m going to keep researching and learning but I may skip LESS on this project. Who knows, maybe it won’t be so bad and I use it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week Notes 4</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2014 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-04/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Week Notes #4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traveled this week which means two things. Got nothing done and learned that I can get a lot of nothing done with an iPad.
&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being nomadic is an interesting concept for a distributed workforce.  I work from home and don’t venture out to coffee shops or other remote areas so traveling while still meeting other obligations is an interesting challenge.  Unfortunately, the obligations I’m talking about are work related; I wasn’t able to work on my own leveling up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was able to use this whole experience as an experiment on working nomadically.  First of all, my work laptop failed miserably - the wireless card is crap on this laptop.  Thanks to GIT, I was able to do work, do some minor testing (our app requires access to a remote database), and commit locally.  However, I wasn’t able to push my commits to Github.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For our standups I used Zoom on the iPad.  In fact, the iPad turned out to work out very well for writing code and other tasks like writing documentation or updating Jira.  After a few hours of fiddling with the laptop, I gave up and switched to using the iPad completely.  My work is backed up to Dropbox but since only the iPad could access the web, the little work I churned out via the laptop was not backed up right away. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although there doesn’t seem to be a native/easy way to commit or push from the iPad, I could have used my work desktop via Citrix.  I don’t like the idea of relying on a remote machine.  There are many possible failure points: the computer itself, the network it’s on, the Citrix server, and everything in between.  This is really the only chink in the armor but it’s a chink that is hard to hit (this metaphor isn’t working for me…). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was thinking of doing some SASS/LESS work in Wakanda this week.  One task requires me to do some CSS work and thought it would be a good time to bring in the last piece of the puzzle. I am using Gulp to compile CoffeeScript, so using LESS was next on my “To Do” list anyway. Should be fun.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week Notes 3</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2014 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-03/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Week Notes #3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wrestled with setting up WordPress locally to create a small temporary application.
&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, I installed WordPress locally using Yeoman, which was super easy. I like using PHP’s built in web server for testing and developing but something about my PHP installation didn’t seem to like the MySQL installation I had. Found out that I didn’t have the &lt;code&gt;PHP.ini&lt;/code&gt; file properly configured for use of MySQL. Updating that got me going with WordPress locally.  The next step is to use Gulp to automate the server startup and I’d like to backup the &lt;code&gt;wp-contents&lt;/code&gt; folder as well, either through a commit or through a copy/paste/rename action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love my job. I love my industry. Web application engineering is fun, intriguing, and exciting. Yet, there is &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; much drama in our field. Lately, I’ve struggled with how to handle some big names in the field pushing their opinions or agenda. On the one hand, they are completely allowed their opinions. On the other hand, people don’t seem to think for themselves and will choose to follow anyone blindly.  I suppose this dynamic is part of the human condition, but it doesn’t make it any less painful to watch.  I bring this up only as a passing thought; it’s something I think that requires more discussion for a later post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week Notes 2</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2014 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-02/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Week Two&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worked with Gulp. Field Notes are awesome! Fiddled with Yeoman to install WordPress locally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like Gulp more than Grunt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enjoy playing with command line but I’m not a fan of using it heavily for certain tasks.  That aside, my biggest problem with Grunt is the unstandardized way that people can set configurations for tasks. Using a tilde or a dash and a specific keyword can modify a plugin in many ways. Sometimes these commands are documented sometimes you have to look over their code. Again, I have no problem with sifting through code (when required) but documenting your product is an important part of delivering the product.  Gulp’s m.o. is to focus on code over configuration. Loads easier to work with. In fact, I was able to create a script to process my entire publishing workflow with Wintersmith. It’s not a 100% but it will get there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use Field Notes for a lot of stuff. I’ve converted the wife even! From a design stand point, they are a lot of fun to collect and even more of a delight to use.  I am so excited to see a larger version come out in the limited edition Colors items. Ordered a few extras above what I already get from my subscription.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeoman is my next project. I am creating a quick app with WordPress and I’m looking for a quick way to get started. I was hoping Yeoman would be my one stop shop but it looks like I still need to do some extra work. Not too big of a deal if I learn how to use Yeoman better. Afterwards, I’d like to make my own generator.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publishing Wintersmith with Gulp - Version 1</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/publishing-with-gulp-and-wintersmith/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2014 20:31:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/publishing-with-gulp-and-wintersmith/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I didn’t get all of my must-have items but I was able to get most of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gulpfile does all of my bare minimum tasks except for one thing - committing and pushing to the github pages repository.  Since I have my versioning split into three different repos and the gulp-git module assumes that the location of the gulpfile &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; the repository home (I think…), it fails since I don’t have a repo there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;https://gist.github.com/Guamaso/a8717f5085c0728f91c0.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was hoping to change the current working directory to the actual repo folder but I’m not sure how or if this is possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;rename&lt;/code&gt; module is a life savor for working with Wintersmith. Moving articles from my &lt;code&gt;articles&lt;/code&gt; folder to the &lt;code&gt;wintersmith&lt;/code&gt; folder was easier than I originally thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;run-Wintersmith&lt;/code&gt; module was a bit tricky. I’m not certain why but npm was erroring out during install.  I added &lt;code&gt;wintersmith&lt;/code&gt; as a dependency to my gulpfile and copied the &lt;code&gt;index.js&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;package.json&lt;/code&gt; files manually to the incomplete folder within &lt;code&gt;node-modules&lt;/code&gt;. It’s a hack but it works; I can successfully run &lt;code&gt;wintersmith.build()&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The very next step is to get git working. Right after that is spell checking. Later on, I’d like to add better handling of the articles.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My &lt;code&gt;articles/published&lt;/code&gt; folder should always win. In other words, the &lt;code&gt;wintersmith/content/articles&lt;/code&gt; folder should match only what is in the published files and nothing more. During testing, a draft article snuck in my wintersmith folder even though it wasn’t in my published folder. This should be rare once I’m done testing but I’d still like to catch it instead of having a draft article get published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until then, I am currently running git commands manually. This isn’t &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; big of a deal as my main purpose was to have an article structure that could be managed easily.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wintersmith kind of kills me in that I can’t group articles in a folder. I wanted to have articles grouped by year, for example.  So, a blog post from 2013 would show up as &lt;code&gt;domain.com/2013/my-blog-post/&lt;/code&gt;. If it can do this, I have not found how.  Wintersmith does not support drafts - which actually makes sense, I’m just surprised I haven’t seen many solutions for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either way, the script provides about 70% of what I set out to do, so I’d call this a solid and productive day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Gulp, Wintersmith tasks</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/learning-gulp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2014 13:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/learning-gulp/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I like command line but as a consumer of some products, I prefer a GUI. Automated tasks runners like Grunt and Gulp, in my opinion should have a GUI for consumers (read: developers). I’ve seen some early work and attempts but nothing very usable. So, here I am learning one of them because, through all my complaining, I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; need to learn them.
&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like learning a new thing by implementing it in something I am already working on.  I figured automating some of my dev journal workflow made sense. Since Wintersmith doesn’t really &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; drafts, I figured Gulp could help out a bit.  So, I worked out the tasks that I &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; I need in order to make publish easier via Github Pages and Wintersmith.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not all the steps are required right now, like testing each published article for example.  In fact, some of these steps I’d like to wrap as a plugin. But that’s for later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started out with the following file structure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dev_journal - root&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;articles - holds markdown articles&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;drafts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;scheduled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;published&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;github_pages - “production”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;wintersmith - holds published articles and template&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;build&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;template&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three git repos, one for the root &lt;code&gt;articles&lt;/code&gt; folder, one for the &lt;code&gt;wintersmith\template&lt;/code&gt; folder, and one for the &lt;code&gt;github_pages&lt;/code&gt; folder.  I could probably consolidate these down to two, maybe even one repo but I’m doing this in baby steps. :)  All of the gulp and package files live in root.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tasks are written out with every step I &lt;strong&gt;want&lt;/strong&gt; in my workflow. But I don’t have the time to learn and get all of it working so I’m focusing on the moving of files first. I will fine tune and improve as I go along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;gulp-task-process-drafts&quot;&gt;Gulp Task: Process Drafts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grab all files from &lt;code&gt;articles/drafts&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check spelling and grammar.  Do not continue processing file if errors exist but save a copy of it to &lt;code&gt;articles/drafts&lt;/code&gt; with spelling/grammar suggestions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check metadata of file. Wintersmith has the metadata header which has a few required fields. Do not continue processing file if errors exist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move remaining files to &lt;code&gt;articles/scheduled&lt;/code&gt; folder.  If the header is filled out then it’s ready to be published.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commit changes to the &lt;code&gt;articles&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;gulp-task-process-scheduled-articles&quot;&gt;Gulp Task: Process Scheduled Articles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grab all files from &lt;code&gt;artciles/scheduled&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spellcheck each file.  Create a copy of any file with errors. Move original and copy to &lt;code&gt;articles/drafts&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create folders in &lt;code&gt;wintersmith/content/articles&lt;/code&gt; based on file names of each markdown file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy each file into its respective folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rename each file to “index.md”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run wintersmith build, verify no errors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commit changes to the &lt;code&gt;articles&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;gulp-task-publish-to-github-pages&quot;&gt;Gulp Task: Publish to Github Pages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clear github pages folder (except .git)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy wintersmith/build folder to github pages folder. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commit changes to &lt;code&gt;github_pages&lt;/code&gt; repo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Push changes to GitHub.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wait a few moments (for github pages to update). Maybe this can be a separate task?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check each article to make sure it exists at url and that content is correct.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move scheduled files to the published folder, if they were indeed published.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week Notes 1</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2014 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-01/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Week Notes #1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Week notes are a great cross between journaling and blogging. The goal of keeping yourself accountable to the interwebz and, more importantly, yourself, is a good goal to shoot for.
&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a lot to learn in the world of web development; always something new coming out.  I have a Trello board listing all the applications, frameworks, languages, and tools that I need to, at the very least, become familiar with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I focused on getting caught up with some other articles/posts as well as keeping up with work tasks. Not a whole lot of time spent on learning new things or practicing existing skills (outside of work, anyway).  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are switching over to Wakanda at work and I’m looking to see how I can use things like Grunt/Gulp, SASS, or CoffeeScript with it.  The application is fairly robust and flexible… ish.  I was able to get Foundation working with it some time ago, as well as Mustache.  I even used CoffeeScript for a module script I had to write.  I’m just not sure how to fit in these tools seamlessly with the built in server. It will probably require a custom plugin.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blocking Right Click Is Just Bad</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/right-click-blocking-is-bad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/right-click-blocking-is-bad/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My uncle’s family owns their own successful restaurant back in California. Really great Mexican food. Most dishes are authentic to the area they are from back in Mexico. Other dishes are hybrids to cater to different tastes but it’s all good grub!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, every now and then, I’ll look at websites of people I know and look for stuff to mock and cajole.  By mock and cajole, I mean to say, analyze and learn what NOT to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exciting part is to see their site using a more mobile first approach. The site is responsive, albeit a little clunky.  Even the obvious stock photography isn’t that bad. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was impressed. So, here I go to try and look up the agency that created the site. I scroll to the footer, find the typical “Designed by” link and right click on it when suddenly… BOOM. Browser alert message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s what it says: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;XXXXX does not allow you to copy or extract any information and/or images from this website.**PLEASE DO NOT TRY THIS ACTION AGAIN**&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I personally know the owners and even I felt a little miffed by the assumption that I was going to steal their horrible stock photos… or the photos of my Uncle with his hugantic cheezer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the deal, most users don’t want to steal. Most users might want to print the page using right click. Or, in my case, open a link in new tab.  Maybe they want to copy your phone number to the clipboard to save into some phone book application.  There are a number of use cases that require the right click which means that by disabling it with a blatantly rude message results in a poor experience for your site and, in turn, your brand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What about the people that &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; want to steal my stuff?” Try this: Hold down CTRL+S. You just stole your stuff. Are you going to block the CTRL key now too? Are you aware that I can disrupt the code that blocks the right click?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to understand how the internet works. The browser is receiving files from the internet, specifically a computer somewhere that holds your site. These files are delivered and the connection between the browser and the server is closed. Guess what? Those files now exist on the person’s computer. The user didn’t need to right click to steal them; they’re already there! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People that want to steal photos of my Uncle holding an awesome plate of seafood with the restaurant logo underneath are going to steal it. There is nothing you can do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What you are doing, though, is creating a bad experience for the legit people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-notes&quot;&gt;Final Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reviewing the code that handles the alert, I found this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;lang-javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;(closeWin==&lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;&quot;1&quot;&lt;/span&gt;) self.close();
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If &lt;code&gt;closeWin&lt;/code&gt; is set to &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt;, the tab will close. WOW. You have just fired your customer before they became your customer. You essentially threw away money. Bravo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/Guamaso/11240273&quot;&gt;whole script&lt;/a&gt; I mined out of the site. It seems like it is a snippet grabbed from someone else, otherwise I wouldn’t use it without permission.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hello World!</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/helloworld/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/helloworld/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I like Ruby in the same way that I like craft/micro beers. I actually don’t like beer, but I like the idea that there is a growing trend for something better than your mass produced, corn syrup sweetened, GMO wheat fermentation. Ruby’s great… but I’m more of a hard cider guy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I thought I’d try using Wintersmith with Github Pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And look at that… works pretty good! :D&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>