<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Juan's Dev Journal</title>
    <atom:link href="http://dev.endgamestudio.com//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
    <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com/</link>
    <description>Dev journal, snippets, and rants.</description>
    <pubDate>Sat, 16  Aug 2014 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <generator>Wintersmith - https://github.com/jnordberg/wintersmith</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>First Meetup Presentation</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/Meetup-talk-aar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16  Aug 2014 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/Meetup-talk-aar/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;first-meetup-presentation-after-action-review&quot;&gt;First Meetup Presentation After Action Review&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first heard of an AAR (&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/After-action_review&quot;&gt;After Action Review&lt;/a&gt; from my wife while she was in the Army. Years later, I joined a team that used the Agile method and became accustomed to sprint retrospectives.  I like the retrospective concept as a method of reviewing the self and the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve said before that this journal’s purpose is partially to help me improve and learn. I meet a lot of people that are afraid to voice their thoughts for fear of being wrong and coming off as a fool. I am one such person. But I never feel that people expressing their thoughts, no matter how raw that thought is, that they themselves are fools. It takes strength and courage to put yourself out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In these situations, though, one needs to look critically at one’s performance and be brutally honest in order to improve.  I hesitated for a moment about putting my thoughts on the Meetup, I’m pretty embarrassed about my performance.  I then remembered the spiel I give to many people about learning web design and development, failure is growth! I immediately decided that I need to be candid about my feelings, thoughts, and decisions regarding my presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am using the format I found on Wikipedia for AAR. They use slightly better verbiage than I would have used. :) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;grunt-gulp-meetup-aar&quot;&gt;Grunt/Gulp Meetup AAR&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok. Here we go… :D  Most of these are my own opinions, many people said it was good (which was very kind of them to say, but I think they were being TOO kind. Thanks to all who said so, though. I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; appreciate the kindness!).  I could be off on some of this stuff… but I really doubt it. ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-was-supposed-to-happen&quot;&gt;What was supposed to happen&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had slides with examples and some step-by-step processes for learning and using Grunt and Gulp.  I was supposed to run through the slides, use my notes for help (if needed), and run through the examples in between some of the slides.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The slides and my speech would help guide attendees attention from one concept to the next. With each slide, we were to build on the previous concept, ultimately working up to an automation task using Gulp and Grunt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On some slides, I had queues that would tell me when to flip over to command line or Sublime (text editor) to go over the examples.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At the end of the slides, I would go over any more examples and questions the audience had.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-happened&quot;&gt;What happened&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I set up the PC to display in extended mode. The slideshow on the project and my notes on my screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I started off OK. Jumped straight into the slides was doing fine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The extended mode caught me off guard, I practiced using one monitor so I assumed everyone could see what I was seeing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I could gauge the audience’s response to some things I would say. I saw blank stares, confused stares, or bored stares.  I tried to adapt to this by trying to explain some extra detail of whatever concept I was explaining at the time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I got ahead of my slides when going through some command line code - before I had set up the concepts for the step I had mistakenly moved on to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I remembered &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; of my queues to flip over to a different application, not all of them. I stammered when this happened.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The text from command line, Sublime, and Far were too small on the projector.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I digressed… A LOT.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I explained a concept and moved on to the next… abruptly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I felt like I struggled explaining the concepts even though I understand them and use them all the time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was flipping between a command prompt (which I did not intend to use), Far Manager, and Sublime… a LOT.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There was a storm that knocked out the power momentarily. At this point, I switched to mirrored mode for the display.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The overall theme of the presentation changed as we went along, making it unclear and confusing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s probably a lot more but it all falls under the same stuff above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-are-some-improves&quot;&gt;What are some improves&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practice explaining the core concepts before even working on the slides.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write the entire presentation as a blog article first. I get my thoughts out better in writing, so an article should be the start of the presentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I practiced by myself, maybe practice in front of people? Like friends, perhaps?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I practiced the transitions from slides to text editor, but it was not in a “live” mentality; I would say to myself “and switch to sublime here”… instead of actually doing it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have queues that tell me to flip BACK to the slides.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practice the examples more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I actually volunteered to do just Gulp. It was recommended to do Gulp &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; Grunt. This was a great idea, but I am not familiar with Grunt like I am with Gulp. I should have agreed but asked to do my talk in two months instead of the one. This would have given me more time to become familiar with Grunt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practice. Practice. PRACTICE…. THEN PRACTICE AGAIN.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-are-some-sustains&quot;&gt;What are some sustains&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m having trouble with this section…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Um… I think I had pretty good eye contact?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think that I know my tools pretty well. I was nervous, but I know how to use Sublime and command line.  I didn’t hesitate with those except when I couldn’t see the result during the time I was using “mirrored” mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I feel like I gave honest answers to audience questions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don’t take myself too seriously in public, which, I hope, makes people feel more comfortable. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-can-i-do-differently-next-time&quot;&gt;What can I do differently next time&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be honest about an achievable time line.  This I had to learn. I don’t think I could have known that I would not have been able to become familiar with Grunt in that time.  But, now I do.  So, next time, be frank about needing more time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practice. EVERY. DAMNED. DAY.  I think I practiced a lot, but I made changes with almost every run through. I wonder if part of my problem was that I should have gotten to the point where changes were minute or nonexistent before I could say I was actually &lt;em&gt;practicing&lt;/em&gt;.  Either way, I think practice would have made this go way more smoothly as I can just run through things instinctively without having to think hard about my next step.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practice with an 800*600 screen, make sure anything I am going to display (especially if it has text) that it is bumped up to as large as possible, so everyone can see.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use black on white text? I think projectors with poor lighting display this better. Command line, Sublime, and Far all had dark backgrounds and white text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t use an “extended” display mode. Stick to mirrored!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a basic slide and example ready &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; volunteering for a meetup.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Invite friends over for dinner, then sucker them into listening/watching my practice. :D&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Record myself during practice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Record myself during actual presentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-thoughts&quot;&gt;Final thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, it sounds like I’m saying I didn’t practice enough. Seems legit.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A while back, I went to a meetup where the speaker was, well, not that great.  As I thought this, though, I immediately thought that this person is up there giving a talk… which is more than I have done.  A friendly person echoed that statement to me right after I finished and it raised my spirits. Sure, I sucked, but I did it. I finished. And, by gum, I’ll improve!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also wanted to note that everyone’s general friendliness is another reason why I am excited to be a web developer. Nothing but encouragement from people - it’s a great feeling to have supportive peers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 11</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16  Aug 2014 08:24:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-11/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grunt/Gulp Talk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consolidated sites to Digital Ocean&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explored Laddr&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;grunt-gulp-talk&quot;&gt;Grunt/Gulp Talk&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did my talk. If I measured the success of a talk in that I didn’t run out in fear and didn’t get “boo’d” off the “stage”… then I succeeded!  It was hard for me to gage if the audience understood the concepts I was trying to present.  A lot of people did, I got this just from talking with them. Some, people, I could see, were struggling.  I take that as a personal failing and it inspired me to write a After Action Review. I’ll post that up later today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;consolidated-sites-to-digital-ocean&quot;&gt;Consolidated sites to Digital Ocean&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital Ocean doesn’t have redundancies and, so far, they seem to have issues more often than not. It is marketed as a developer VPS solution, which, to me, says stability is not to be expected. And you know what? That’s ok. It’s good enough and it is insanely cheap.  The sites that I put on there aren’t popular even by any definition, so if they go down even for a few hours here and there, it should be fine.  If they grow in popularity (ha! Right…) then it will make more sense to move them over to something else. Maybe AWS or A Small Orange (they have a similar plan at $20 but with redundant hardware, for example).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital Ocean has a ton of great guides for installing all sorts of things. Ghost 0.5 was just released so they are missing the updated version number, but the process is the same. I learned how to have multiple Ghost instances running under one NginX server and how to configure them all as services. I &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; their “droplet” interface as well. Even with having to use command line for the server itself, their interface is so much easier to use then cPanel (I was told that you can install a GUI and use that to admin the server, but I’m starting to like command line!). Here’s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitalocean.com/?refcode=ef003a64b58d&quot;&gt;referral sign up link&lt;/a&gt; if you’re interested, which you should be. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;explored-laddr&quot;&gt;Explored Laddr&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laddr is nifty PHP app that helps Code for America Brigades keep track of their projects, conversations, and other stuff. It was created as a Code for America project (I think?) in Philadelphia.  As I said before, I’m helping out with the Cary Brigade and the first area I’m helping out with is the front end to the Brigade’s website.  Laddr is commonly placed on the root domain for many Brigades. We’re not set up for that now but we might in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m curious how Laddr and Github will mesh as far as communication on bugs and features.  The administration page is nifty. I can edit the PHP templating and other code easily through this back end page. I’ll get to really dig in this weekend and I’m super exited.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 10</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10  Aug 2014 08:24:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-10/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Missed my Friday deadline&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grunt/Gulp Talk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meditation and rest&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;missed-my-friday-deadline&quot;&gt;Missed my Friday deadline&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to have these written by Friday night, just as a personal goal. I’m a little stressed out on my first talk next week, but I’ll get to that.  I feel like it’s ok to miss deadlines from time to time, provided that it isn’t a common occurrence. The problem, I think, we run into when we’re late on something is trying to get caught up.  We’re so busy that falling behind on one thing puts everything else behind as well. That’s why it’s important to build a buffer or… wait for it… a graceful fallback! :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At work, we have periodic “non-sprints” where we aren’t in a sprint and aren’t expected to complete story points.  We can work the backlog or do some research on backlog items.  I’m no agile expert, so I don’t know how close this follows the agile method or if the terms are correct. Anyway, I think that in anything we do, it’s important to be able to do one of two things (or both, really): claim to do bankruptcy or have a non-work week.  I’m not behind on my personal projects… or work projects for that matter, but being late for my weeknotes made me think about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;grunt-gulp-talk&quot;&gt;Grunt/Gulp Talk&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m practicing my talk for this Tuesday the 12th.  I’m psyched. I’m nervous. I want to get back to Code for Cary so I’m excited for two reasons. Being able to share my thoughts on Gulp/Grunt/automation, but also be able to redirect my attention to other things. Being my first talk, I’ve given this &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of attention. I’m not complaining, it’s just the fact of the past few weeks. Anyway, I’m planning on throwing the talk and all my materials, including articles I researched for the talk, on github.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;meditation-and-rest&quot;&gt;Meditation and rest&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with being able to take a non-work work week or being able to claim task bankruptcy, it’s also important to have complete non-work time.  Along with doing mind dumps, I have started doing meditation and introspection time.  Straight up sleep is still a work in progress but it’s high priority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned meditation in an Aikido class I took a long time ago and I liked the peace and tranquility I got from it. It’s a struggle trying to keep your mind clear, but it’s a good healthy struggle.  Keeping balance in your mind is like a muscle that one needs to exercise in order for it to work efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once my mind is clear (ish… I still can’t really achieve complete calmness), I will do a mind dump.  I just write down every thought that comes back. Some thoughts are “to dos”, some are ideas, and some are personal introspections.  It’s these personal thoughts that I am going for. Understanding why I think things or why I have problems in certain parts of my life are very important to self improvement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does this have to do with software? Software engineering is problem solving. Problem solving is a muscle, too.  It requires higher reasoning and a balanced mind, in my opinion, which some people have inherently, or, like me, have to work hard at it.  I found that meditation and introspection help improve your ability to focus and problem solve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also makes you feel better. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 9</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01  Aug 2014 10:24:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-09/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 9&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grunt/Gulp Talk is a go&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installed Ubuntu server on old netbook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Playing with Yo API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;grunt-gulp-talk-is-a-go&quot;&gt;Grunt/Gulp Talk is a go&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m struggling with what my actual goal is. In researching the topic, I realized it is actually fairly easy to learn how to use both Gulp and Grunt. The problem is first understanding the concepts of tasks and NPM and dependencies.  The other problem I feel web craftsfolk face is trying to stay in sync with the available toolset without losing momentum in other things like life etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have two choices then. Take this talk with the literal “Gulp and Grunt” description and just discuss the differences. Or, I can use this as a vehicle to show how important it is to take that first step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suppose I could do both. :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;installed-ubuntu-server-on-old-netbook&quot;&gt;Installed Ubuntu server on old netbook&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has been on the back burner for a while. I have wanted a portable web server for a while now. My netbook isn’t used for much these days except as a print server.  After bringing up a server through Digital Ocean, I realized I could have done the netbook first as a learning experience.  Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t expect to have so much fun with this.  That feeling when something works, almost like the atypical comic book regular person discovering they have a super power that can help the world.  I can use it to test APIs, work as a staging server, or serve local pages for home stuff. In order to do this, though, I am saying that it is no longer a computer; it is strictly my server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;playing-with-yo-api&quot;&gt;Playing with Yo API&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the tests I used while playing with the web server was playing with the Yo API. There’s not much to it but I thought I could use it on the web server to check my main server and “Yo” me when the main server is out.  I thought it would be fun to publicize a Yo address that updated a website with people that have Yo’d that address. The point is, it’s a toy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 8</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 10:24:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-08/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 8&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created Wakanda data import tool&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Started work on Gulp/Grunt talk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up Ember environment with Yeoman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;created-wakanda-data-import-tool&quot;&gt;Created Wakanda data import tool&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t find a way to easily import data from one server to another that was required by parts of the application. &lt;a href=&quot;http://dev.endgamestudio.com/Wakanda-Import-Concept/&quot;&gt;I created a datastore class method&lt;/a&gt; the read a JSON file and import any missing records.  It’s a great first step for our team if we decide to continue using Wakanda local datastores (versus remote datastores).  I think that these local datastores are great, faster, less cumbersome, and more powerful. But that’s not my call. :(&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;started-gulp-grunt-talk&quot;&gt;Started Gulp/Grunt talk&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finished my outline and now in the process of adding more and more detail. Still nothing to link to yet which is good. I feel that it’s not a &lt;em&gt;thing&lt;/em&gt; until there is a link which keeps my nerves in check.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;set-up-ember-environment-with-yeoman&quot;&gt;Set up Ember environment with Yeoman&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I freak out at the shear amount of &lt;em&gt;stuff&lt;/em&gt; Yeoman loads in a folder after it is done running a generator. The Grunt file alone is insane. Once I looked through it, though, it made sense. The same goes for the rest of the objects in the project folder. Anyway, I loaded up an Ember generator to use EmberFire on it.  Get to fiddle with that tonight actually.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wakanda Data Import</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/Wakanda-Import-Concept/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 10:01:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/Wakanda-Import-Concept/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;wakanda-data-import-tool&quot;&gt;Wakanda Data Import Tool&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When new data is created to support the application, not user data, we need a way to update servers down the deployment chain.  With SQL, this was easy… ish. A versioned query that was part of the deployment handled the task.  With Wakanda, we could do the same thing. &lt;em&gt;OR&lt;/em&gt; we could take a step higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was tasked with creating a bare bones rights engine for our app. In it, I had to display error messages to the user. I don’t like hardcoding messages, I prefer to let the client edit them whenever possible.  I created the solution for this but then ran into a problem syncing data across development and test servers - which meant we were going to run into a problem syncing the data to production… once we reached that point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I created a &lt;a href=&quot;http://doc.wakanda.org/Datastore-Model-Designer/Datastore-Class-Methods.300-473312.en.html&quot;&gt;Datastore class method&lt;/a&gt; that checked for a JSON file and imported any required data into the target datastore. It worked great. A couple of issues did come up like exposing the method to the client and abstracting the schema of the table from the import process. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having the method exposed to the client is dangerous for many reasons, most importantly being that our team is still new to Wakanda, which is also still in its infancy.  The solution is to be able to call the method from the server itself. Or easily disable the method once the app is in “production” mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The schema part I’m still debating on how to handle. I can include the schema in the import file. I could verify the schema based on the key/value pairs in the data itself.  The main task is complete and was approved so the next time I have to do something similar, I’ll go in and clean it up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;https://gist.github.com/Guamaso/7d80034a24f50eaee1bf.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 7</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2014 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-07/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 7: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wakanda Training&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gulp and Grunt Talk Brief&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fiddling with Firebase&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Signed up for Digital Ocean&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;wakanda-training&quot;&gt;Wakanda Training&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of the week, I attended a two day training at work on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wakanda.org/&quot;&gt;Wakanda&lt;/a&gt;.  The two days reminded me of what they say about Calculus: &lt;em&gt;it’s like 90% Algebra&lt;/em&gt;.  Wakanda training (Wakanda being based on a JavaScript stack) was 90% JavaScript.  It was a good refresh for myself and a very good one-oh-one-esque course for some of our “desktop” developers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sidebar: are they called “desktop” developers? I’ve heard them being referred to as “system language” developers. My point is, they are not web developers by trade.  Writing code for the web can be very different.  Throw in HTML markup and CSS styling and web applications get even tougher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the training was good. It was also good to hang out with the team for a while in RL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;gulp-and-grunt-meetup-talk-brief&quot;&gt;Gulp and Grunt Meetup Talk Brief&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote up the brief, created my main bullet points and started working on the deck itself.  I’m excited but I’m also very nervous. This is an interesting experiment - I don’t do public speaking.  The Dev Journal’s goal was to improve how I learn.  Having to publicize my thoughts forces me to think deeper about what I’m going to say. Doing a public speaking event, even something as humble as a local meetup, seems to be having the same effect but in multiples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I submitted the brief and received a positive note. I’m waiting for the Meetup page to get updated before I put my nose to the grindstone on the presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;fiddling-with-firebase&quot;&gt;Fiddling with Firebase&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I updated the code that feeds a random haiku on my home page. I’m trying to make it so I can link to specific haiku’s I write.  Learning a lot about refactoring and how fun it is to shoot yourself in the foot. :&amp;lt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;signed-up-for-digital-ocean&quot;&gt;Signed up for Digital Ocean&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a web server that runs WordPress but I am not a fan of cPanel. It seems that I have come to prefer command line and direct access to the server. I heard about Digital Ocean from the Wakanda training and immediately purchased a droplet.  For five dollars, I am able to purchase a virtual server with not-so-bad specs.  Once the shared web server is up, I will bump up the specs in order to host WordPress &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; a couple of Ghost instances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m writing up a list of what I did to get going with a droplet. I had about 2 days, cumulative, experience with running Linux through command line. There is a lot to write about from my experience. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes 6</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2014 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-06/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 6: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More Meetups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publishing through Wintersmith with Gulp updated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Github question/thought&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;more-meetups&quot;&gt;More Meetups&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I try to go to as many Meetups as I possibly can.  There are many in Durham for topics such as JavaScript and more. Unfortunately, those Meetups are a bit more difficult for me to make consistently.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/designcrop/&quot;&gt;Crop&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/functionpink/&quot;&gt;Function Pink&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/WebDesign2-0/&quot;&gt;Web Design&lt;/a&gt;, and (now) &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Triangle-Code-for-America/&quot;&gt;Code for Cary&lt;/a&gt; I try my hardest to make, wherever they are held.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Triangle-JavaScript/&quot;&gt;Triangle JavaScript&lt;/a&gt; is also a good one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am helping out the Code for Cary brigade which is fun.  I made a comment on my first Meetup with them that there aren’t enough “doing” Meetups, just lots of “conversation” or “presentation” Meetups - which is fine, but we definitely need more “doing” Meetups.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Web Design Meetup asked for presentations and I thought now would be a good time to put up.  I have learned a lot regarding Gulp and I figured doing a presentation is the next step in my progression.  So, I volunteered. I need to create a brief and send it to Pepper and hopefully she and her fellow organizers will like it.  In addition to the existing &lt;a href=&quot;http://dev.endgamestudio.com/articles/project-mind-dump/&quot;&gt;projects I wrote about&lt;/a&gt; the other day, I now have added a presentation to the list. Good times! No sarcasm there, I love this stuff!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;publishing-through-wintersmith-with-gulp&quot;&gt;Publishing through Wintersmith with Gulp&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I updated the script after finally getting Aspell properly installed on my machine.  I’m not sure if I did something wrong during install (I don’t think I did) but the system path wasn’t updated with the Aspell &lt;code&gt;bin&lt;/code&gt; location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With added spell checking support, I also improved the Gulpfile with better handling of articles as they move through my workflow.  I need to clean it up a bit and then update the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/Guamaso/a8717f5085c0728f91c0&quot;&gt;Gulpfile Gist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d also like to make a web interface for it that let’s me edit and process the spell check results in the browser.  Add that to the backlog, I suppose. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;github-thought-question&quot;&gt;Github thought/question&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I work from either &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; or from a branch I create (typically &lt;code&gt;dev&lt;/code&gt;). New versions or releases come as tags.  I don’t see the benefit to keeping versions in their own branch.  New work, fixes, or sandboxes: yes, but not old versions.  This is all raw thought; I haven’t done any research on this yet, so I could be wrong. Still, when I find a repo that uses this, I would expect the most recent version to be set to master, not some version in the middle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found a repo that I needed for work and I noticed that the master branch seemed odd.  The structure didn’t match what I was using in their commercial product.  I submitted an issue without looking through their branches. If I had, I would have found that the stuff I was looking for was in a branch.  I feel like there should have been a &lt;code&gt;readme.md&lt;/code&gt; file to explain their structure and the product itself. I admit, I should have looked through the branches first.  I still think it’s a weird way to structure a repo but it is on me to look before I leap. Lesson learned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, this same repo’s owner left a comment on a prior issue that the project’s bug tracker was elsewhere.  Yet, Github’s issue tracker was on. It just makes me feel like they put stuff on Github to attract attention to the product - which is perfectly fine, but if this is the business plan, ya’ gotta commit 100% (no pun intended). People should create a mental model quickly and with little effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could be wrong on all of this but I doubt I am wrong on everything… just some of it. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project Mind Dump</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/project-mind-dump/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 14:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/project-mind-dump/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I suffer from “Oh shinny” disease. Symptoms include taking on too many new projects, tasks, or challenges.  There is no cure, but symptoms can be alleviated somewhat by sitting down and doing a mind dump.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use mind dumps to get everything out onto something I can organize and prioritize.  In this case, in keeping with the purpose of the Dev Journal, I want to keep myself accountable for what I have taken on.  So, I’m also including a quick status update on the different projects I’ve started within the past couple months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;wordpress-via-yeoman&quot;&gt;WordPress via Yeoman&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I originally wanted to create a simple web app for an data import I am working on.  My first goal was to install WordPress using Yeoman. That worked great. The next goal was to be able to initiate a simple PHP web server for development using the install location as the web root.  This proved difficult due to my limited understanding of the built in PHP web server, MySQL server, and XAMPP.  I did eventually get that to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last goal before actually being able to start working was to understand how to access data within the WordPress tables using nothing but the WordPress API’s (maybe some plugins, if needed). This is where work ceased on this project. I found that my time was better spent learning &lt;a href=&quot;http://emberjs.com/&quot;&gt;Ember.js&lt;/a&gt; and building an app that way.  Still, I would like to establish a good workflow using WordPress. Something that includes a PHP web server, MySQL server, and anything else one would need to work with WordPress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll look to &lt;a href=&quot;http://bower.io/&quot;&gt;Bower&lt;/a&gt; for this and report back… when I can.  This is low priority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;gulp-and-publishing-via-wintersmith&quot;&gt;Gulp and Publishing via Wintersmith&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mentioned before why I’m not a fan of Grunt.  Things like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/substack/stream-handbook&quot;&gt;“streams”&lt;/a&gt; and “vinyl” files confuse me a bit but I still prefer Gulp over Grunt.  Maybe that is due to my style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I worked a good deal on my script that helps publish articles with &lt;a href=&quot;http://wintersmith.io/&quot;&gt;Wintersmith&lt;/a&gt;.  There are two items left on my To Do list, getting the spell check working and more awareness of what articles are &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; published.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is still ongoing and it’s actually very rewarding. I was not aware of streams and it’s a good way to learn more about Node.js.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;code-for-cary-page&quot;&gt;Code for Cary page&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I attended a meetup and offered my assistance with some of their front end problems. I thought the page was great as Robert, the creator of the page and co-captain of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Triangle-Code-for-America/&quot;&gt;Code for Cary brigade&lt;/a&gt;, said he learned how to implement a new script that used a slider affect when the user scrolls the page.  We always focus on whether a page (or product) is good based on the experience for the end user is.  This is a good measure but it’s not the only one.  Learning how to use something and when to apply it is a success. The end user may not like it which is a failure according to that first measure but even that is useful. Failures are only a failure if you don’t learn from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I digress. I’m updating the page and really want to use LESS instead of straight CSS. I’m still working on this as well. This is actually number one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;writing-moar-&quot;&gt;Writing moar…&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like writing. I love it. I suck at it, though.  I suck at web development, too, though.  And this journal’s purpose is to help me learn web development as much as it is to help me learn to write more better. (I did that on purpose…)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I write in a few different places which may contribute to the problem of not writing more often. Although, I don’t feel like three places is a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I write about creativity in one spot, video games in another, and web dev here.  Not too bad.  My goal is one article a month for each site. With as many minor posts as possible. This, in case you were wondering, is a minor post. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really just need to shut up and write more. This is an ongoing thing, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;mentoring&quot;&gt;Mentoring&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like I said, I’m not that great. I don’t have my own agency, I haven’t organized my own conference, or made any major contributions to the community really.  I made peace with my inability to keep up with others skill-wise.  I know the saying, there is always someone smarter than you, but that’s not what this is about. I’m ok with not being an expert at anything.  That doesn’t mean stop learning or trying my best, it just means that I measure my success against myself. I know what I am capable of now and I know what success looks like to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Success looks like helping others develop their skills and confidence.  I meet a lot of people just entering the field with that deer-in-headlights look. They want to know where to start and they’re scared because nothing makes sense.  Been there. I remember it clearly.  I remember thinking how much I would benefit from a mentor.  There are plenty of places to ask questions and get guidance on-line, but let’s be honest, we can be a bunch of jerks sometimes.  I’m getting rant-y so I’ll just finish by saying that we need a better mentoring system.  One that doesn’t require an initiate to have loads of cash (as much as those programs are worth the investment, not everyone has the time or finances to apply).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m doing research on how I can help.  Again, I’m not one of the “greats” by any means, but I got &lt;em&gt;heart&lt;/em&gt;, yo.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week Notes 5</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2014 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-05/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Week Notes #5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Establishing a LESS workflow using Gulp. Found out about Code for America - a really cool thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of leveling up my skills is also leveling up my ability to communicate, lead, and mentor others. I feel that these skills require constant interaction with fellow developers.  Therefore, I attend a lot of meetups… well, as many as I can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://codeforamerica.org/&quot;&gt;Code for America&lt;/a&gt; is a really great organization. Having developed an interest in local government while working for the City of Fayetteville a few years back, I thought it would be interesting to see what the organization had to offer.  There are three Brigades (groups or teams), in the Raleigh/Durham area: Raleigh, Durham, and Cary. It so happened that I was free the night of the Cary meetup.  Meeting with the team of civic-minded folks was great and inspiring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They mentioned needing help with the landing page of the Code for Cary site. I started working on that earlier and thought it would be a great place to learn LESS. Unfortunately, I am a perfectionist.  Through my initial research, I found that using LESS in development requires adding scripts so the files are compiled by the client. This is fine - actually, this is perfect. The problem is, I don’t know what the production environment is like. Which means that I’ll have to compile a build and have that ready for production. That is just too much for a simple page site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m going to keep researching and learning but I may skip LESS on this project. Who knows, maybe it won’t be so bad and I use it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week Notes 4</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2014 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-04/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Week Notes #4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traveled this week which means two things. Got nothing done and learned that I can get a lot of nothing done with an iPad.
&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being nomadic is an interesting concept for a distributed workforce.  I work from home and don’t venture out to coffee shops or other remote areas so traveling while still meeting other obligations is an interesting challenge.  Unfortunately, the obligations I’m talking about are work related; I wasn’t able to work on my own leveling up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was able to use this whole experience as an experiment on working nomadically.  First of all, my work laptop failed miserably - the wireless card is crap on this laptop.  Thanks to GIT, I was able to do work, do some minor testing (our app requires access to a remote database), and commit locally.  However, I wasn’t able to push my commits to Github.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For our standups I used Zoom on the iPad.  In fact, the iPad turned out to work out very well for writing code and other tasks like writing documentation or updating Jira.  After a few hours of fiddling with the laptop, I gave up and switched to using the iPad completely.  My work is backed up to Dropbox but since only the iPad could access the web, the little work I churned out via the laptop was not backed up right away. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although there doesn’t seem to be a native/easy way to commit or push from the iPad, I could have used my work desktop via Citrix.  I don’t like the idea of relying on a remote machine.  There are many possible failure points: the computer itself, the network it’s on, the Citrix server, and everything in between.  This is really the only chink in the armor but it’s a chink that is hard to hit (this metaphor isn’t working for me…). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was thinking of doing some SASS/LESS work in Wakanda this week.  One task requires me to do some CSS work and thought it would be a good time to bring in the last piece of the puzzle. I am using Gulp to compile CoffeeScript, so using LESS was next on my “To Do” list anyway. Should be fun.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week Notes 3</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2014 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-03/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Week Notes #3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wrestled with setting up WordPress locally to create a small temporary application.
&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, I installed WordPress locally using Yeoman, which was super easy. I like using PHP’s built in web server for testing and developing but something about my PHP installation didn’t seem to like the MySQL installation I had. Found out that I didn’t have the &lt;code&gt;PHP.ini&lt;/code&gt; file properly configured for use of MySQL. Updating that got me going with WordPress locally.  The next step is to use Gulp to automate the server startup and I’d like to backup the &lt;code&gt;wp-contents&lt;/code&gt; folder as well, either through a commit or through a copy/paste/rename action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love my job. I love my industry. Web application engineering is fun, intriguing, and exciting. Yet, there is &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; much drama in our field. Lately, I’ve struggled with how to handle some big names in the field pushing their opinions or agenda. On the one hand, they are completely allowed their opinions. On the other hand, people don’t seem to think for themselves and will choose to follow anyone blindly.  I suppose this dynamic is part of the human condition, but it doesn’t make it any less painful to watch.  I bring this up only as a passing thought; it’s something I think that requires more discussion for a later post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week Notes 2</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2014 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-02/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Week Two&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worked with Gulp. Field Notes are awesome! Fiddled with Yeoman to install WordPress locally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like Gulp more than Grunt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enjoy playing with command line but I’m not a fan of using it heavily for certain tasks.  That aside, my biggest problem with Grunt is the unstandardized way that people can set configurations for tasks. Using a tilde or a dash and a specific keyword can modify a plugin in many ways. Sometimes these commands are documented sometimes you have to look over their code. Again, I have no problem with sifting through code (when required) but documenting your product is an important part of delivering the product.  Gulp’s m.o. is to focus on code over configuration. Loads easier to work with. In fact, I was able to create a script to process my entire publishing workflow with Wintersmith. It’s not a 100% but it will get there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use Field Notes for a lot of stuff. I’ve converted the wife even! From a design stand point, they are a lot of fun to collect and even more of a delight to use.  I am so excited to see a larger version come out in the limited edition Colors items. Ordered a few extras above what I already get from my subscription.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeoman is my next project. I am creating a quick app with WordPress and I’m looking for a quick way to get started. I was hoping Yeoman would be my one stop shop but it looks like I still need to do some extra work. Not too big of a deal if I learn how to use Yeoman better. Afterwards, I’d like to make my own generator.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publishing Wintersmith with Gulp - Version 1</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/publishing-with-gulp-and-wintersmith/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2014 20:31:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/publishing-with-gulp-and-wintersmith/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I didn’t get all of my must-have items but I was able to get most of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gulpfile does all of my bare minimum tasks except for one thing - committing and pushing to the github pages repository.  Since I have my versioning split into three different repos and the gulp-git module assumes that the location of the gulpfile &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; the repository home (I think…), it fails since I don’t have a repo there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;https://gist.github.com/Guamaso/a8717f5085c0728f91c0.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was hoping to change the current working directory to the actual repo folder but I’m not sure how or if this is possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;rename&lt;/code&gt; module is a life savor for working with Wintersmith. Moving articles from my &lt;code&gt;articles&lt;/code&gt; folder to the &lt;code&gt;wintersmith&lt;/code&gt; folder was easier than I originally thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;run-Wintersmith&lt;/code&gt; module was a bit tricky. I’m not certain why but npm was erroring out during install.  I added &lt;code&gt;wintersmith&lt;/code&gt; as a dependency to my gulpfile and copied the &lt;code&gt;index.js&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;package.json&lt;/code&gt; files manually to the incomplete folder within &lt;code&gt;node-modules&lt;/code&gt;. It’s a hack but it works; I can successfully run &lt;code&gt;wintersmith.build()&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The very next step is to get git working. Right after that is spell checking. Later on, I’d like to add better handling of the articles.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My &lt;code&gt;articles/published&lt;/code&gt; folder should always win. In other words, the &lt;code&gt;wintersmith/content/articles&lt;/code&gt; folder should match only what is in the published files and nothing more. During testing, a draft article snuck in my wintersmith folder even though it wasn’t in my published folder. This should be rare once I’m done testing but I’d still like to catch it instead of having a draft article get published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until then, I am currently running git commands manually. This isn’t &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; big of a deal as my main purpose was to have an article structure that could be managed easily.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wintersmith kind of kills me in that I can’t group articles in a folder. I wanted to have articles grouped by year, for example.  So, a blog post from 2013 would show up as &lt;code&gt;domain.com/2013/my-blog-post/&lt;/code&gt;. If it can do this, I have not found how.  Wintersmith does not support drafts - which actually makes sense, I’m just surprised I haven’t seen many solutions for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either way, the script provides about 70% of what I set out to do, so I’d call this a solid and productive day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Gulp, Wintersmith tasks</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/learning-gulp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2014 13:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/learning-gulp/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I like command line but as a consumer of some products, I prefer a GUI. Automated tasks runners like Grunt and Gulp, in my opinion should have a GUI for consumers (read: developers). I’ve seen some early work and attempts but nothing very usable. So, here I am learning one of them because, through all my complaining, I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; need to learn them.
&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like learning a new thing by implementing it in something I am already working on.  I figured automating some of my dev journal workflow made sense. Since Wintersmith doesn’t really &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; drafts, I figured Gulp could help out a bit.  So, I worked out the tasks that I &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; I need in order to make publish easier via Github Pages and Wintersmith.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not all the steps are required right now, like testing each published article for example.  In fact, some of these steps I’d like to wrap as a plugin. But that’s for later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started out with the following file structure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dev_journal - root&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;articles - holds markdown articles&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;drafts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;scheduled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;published&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;github_pages - “production”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;wintersmith - holds published articles and template&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;build&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;template&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three git repos, one for the root &lt;code&gt;articles&lt;/code&gt; folder, one for the &lt;code&gt;wintersmith\template&lt;/code&gt; folder, and one for the &lt;code&gt;github_pages&lt;/code&gt; folder.  I could probably consolidate these down to two, maybe even one repo but I’m doing this in baby steps. :)  All of the gulp and package files live in root.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tasks are written out with every step I &lt;strong&gt;want&lt;/strong&gt; in my workflow. But I don’t have the time to learn and get all of it working so I’m focusing on the moving of files first. I will fine tune and improve as I go along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;gulp-task-process-drafts&quot;&gt;Gulp Task: Process Drafts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grab all files from &lt;code&gt;articles/drafts&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check spelling and grammar.  Do not continue processing file if errors exist but save a copy of it to &lt;code&gt;articles/drafts&lt;/code&gt; with spelling/grammar suggestions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check metadata of file. Wintersmith has the metadata header which has a few required fields. Do not continue processing file if errors exist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move remaining files to &lt;code&gt;articles/scheduled&lt;/code&gt; folder.  If the header is filled out then it’s ready to be published.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commit changes to the &lt;code&gt;articles&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;gulp-task-process-scheduled-articles&quot;&gt;Gulp Task: Process Scheduled Articles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grab all files from &lt;code&gt;artciles/scheduled&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spellcheck each file.  Create a copy of any file with errors. Move original and copy to &lt;code&gt;articles/drafts&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create folders in &lt;code&gt;wintersmith/content/articles&lt;/code&gt; based on file names of each markdown file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy each file into its respective folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rename each file to “index.md”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run wintersmith build, verify no errors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commit changes to the &lt;code&gt;articles&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;gulp-task-publish-to-github-pages&quot;&gt;Gulp Task: Publish to Github Pages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clear github pages folder (except .git)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy wintersmith/build folder to github pages folder. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commit changes to &lt;code&gt;github_pages&lt;/code&gt; repo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Push changes to GitHub.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wait a few moments (for github pages to update). Maybe this can be a separate task?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check each article to make sure it exists at url and that content is correct.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move scheduled files to the published folder, if they were indeed published.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week Notes 1</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2014 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/weeknotes-2014-01/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Week Notes #1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Week notes are a great cross between journaling and blogging. The goal of keeping yourself accountable to the interwebz and, more importantly, yourself, is a good goal to shoot for.
&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a lot to learn in the world of web development; always something new coming out.  I have a Trello board listing all the applications, frameworks, languages, and tools that I need to, at the very least, become familiar with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I focused on getting caught up with some other articles/posts as well as keeping up with work tasks. Not a whole lot of time spent on learning new things or practicing existing skills (outside of work, anyway).  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are switching over to Wakanda at work and I’m looking to see how I can use things like Grunt/Gulp, SASS, or CoffeeScript with it.  The application is fairly robust and flexible… ish.  I was able to get Foundation working with it some time ago, as well as Mustache.  I even used CoffeeScript for a module script I had to write.  I’m just not sure how to fit in these tools seamlessly with the built in server. It will probably require a custom plugin.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blocking Right Click Is Just Bad</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/right-click-blocking-is-bad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/right-click-blocking-is-bad/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My uncle’s family owns their own successful restaurant back in California. Really great Mexican food. Most dishes are authentic to the area they are from back in Mexico. Other dishes are hybrids to cater to different tastes but it’s all good grub!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, every now and then, I’ll look at websites of people I know and look for stuff to mock and cajole.  By mock and cajole, I mean to say, analyze and learn what NOT to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exciting part is to see their site using a more mobile first approach. The site is responsive, albeit a little clunky.  Even the obvious stock photography isn’t that bad. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was impressed. So, here I go to try and look up the agency that created the site. I scroll to the footer, find the typical “Designed by” link and right click on it when suddenly… BOOM. Browser alert message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s what it says: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;XXXXX does not allow you to copy or extract any information and/or images from this website.**PLEASE DO NOT TRY THIS ACTION AGAIN**&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I personally know the owners and even I felt a little miffed by the assumption that I was going to steal their horrible stock photos… or the photos of my Uncle with his hugantic cheezer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the deal, most users don’t want to steal. Most users might want to print the page using right click. Or, in my case, open a link in new tab.  Maybe they want to copy your phone number to the clipboard to save into some phone book application.  There are a number of use cases that require the right click which means that by disabling it with a blatantly rude message results in a poor experience for your site and, in turn, your brand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What about the people that &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; want to steal my stuff?” Try this: Hold down CTRL+S. You just stole your stuff. Are you going to block the CTRL key now too? Are you aware that I can disrupt the code that blocks the right click?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to understand how the internet works. The browser is receiving files from the internet, specifically a computer somewhere that holds your site. These files are delivered and the connection between the browser and the server is closed. Guess what? Those files now exist on the person’s computer. The user didn’t need to right click to steal them; they’re already there! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People that want to steal photos of my Uncle holding an awesome plate of seafood with the restaurant logo underneath are going to steal it. There is nothing you can do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What you are doing, though, is creating a bad experience for the legit people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-notes&quot;&gt;Final Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reviewing the code that handles the alert, I found this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;lang-javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;(closeWin==&lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;&quot;1&quot;&lt;/span&gt;) self.close();
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If &lt;code&gt;closeWin&lt;/code&gt; is set to &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt;, the tab will close. WOW. You have just fired your customer before they became your customer. You essentially threw away money. Bravo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/Guamaso/11240273&quot;&gt;whole script&lt;/a&gt; I mined out of the site. It seems like it is a snippet grabbed from someone else, otherwise I wouldn’t use it without permission.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hello World!</title>
      <link>http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/helloworld/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dev.endgamestudio.com//articles/helloworld/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I like Ruby in the same way that I like craft/micro beers. I actually don’t like beer, but I like the idea that there is a growing trend for something better than your mass produced, corn syrup sweetened, GMO wheat fermentation. Ruby’s great… but I’m more of a hard cider guy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I thought I’d try using Wintersmith with Github Pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And look at that… works pretty good! :D&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>